<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="751" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">ORDINANCES <lb/>ADOPTED BY THE <lb/>CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION <lb/>OF THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>CONVENED AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN, SEPTEMBER 6, 1875.</byline>
<byline>1876</byline>
<pb n="752" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="753" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">ORDINANCES.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>In Relation to Railroads.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the People of Texas in Convention assembled, That in view of the financial misfortunes now existing, no railroad company chartered or holding grants under this State, which has heretofore organized and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced work in good faith, shall be considered as having lost any of its rights, privileges or grants prior to the close of the next session of the Legislature of this State by virtue of lapse of time between now and that time; and said Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature shall have the power, if deemed compatible with the public interest, to grant such relief in time as may be deemed best for the interests of the State; provided, that this ordinance shall not be so construed as to relieve rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road companies from compliance with the conditions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in Article 10 of the Constitution, in relation to rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roads.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ORDINANCE.</head>
<p>No ordinance passed by this Convention and not sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted for the ratification of the people, except that post<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poning the election, and that submitting the Constitution to a vote of the qualified electors, shall, in any sense, be deemed operative, as affecting the rights of the State, or the rights and obligations of any person, association or corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion within the State, or having rights therein, or obliga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereto, either to confirm, release, relieve or modify the same, unless the Constitution shall be ratified by the qualified electors of the State of Texas.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="754" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To Divide the State of Texas into Senatorial and Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tative Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Convention assembled, That until after the first apportion<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of senators and representatives, as provided in this Constitution, after the census of the United States shall have been taken in 1880, the State shall be divided into Senatorial and Representative districts, as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Senatorial Districts.</head>
<p>First District&#8212;The counties of Liberty, Chambers, San Jacinto, Hardin, Tyler, Jefferson, Jasper, Orange, Newton and Polk shall elect one senator; Tyler to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Second District&#8212;The counties of Houston, Angelina, Nacogdoches, San Augustine and Sabine shall elect one sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor; Nacogdoches to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Third District&#8212;The counties of Rusk, Panola and Shelby shall elect one senator; Panola to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fourth District&#8212;The county of Harrison shall elect one senator.</p>
<p>Fifth District&#8212;The counties of Marion, Cass, Bowie and Morris shall elect one senator; Cass to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixth District&#8212;The counties of Red River, Titus, Franklin and Hopkins shall elect one senator; Titus to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Seventh District&#8212;The counties of Camp, Upshur, Gregg and Smith shall elect one senator; Gregg to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Eighth District&#8212;The counties of Cherokee, Anderson and Henderson shall elect one Senator; Anderson to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Ninth District&#8212;The counties of Lamar, Fannin and Delta shall elect one senator; Lamar to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Tenth District&#8212;The counties of Wood, Van Zandt, Kauf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, Raines, Rockwall and Hunt shall elect one senator; Kaufman to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Eleventh District&#8212;The counties of Gray and Cooke shall elect one senator; Grayson to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twelfth District&#8212;The counties of Collin and Denton shall elect one senator; Collin to be the returning county.</p>
<pb n="755" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Thirteenth District&#8212;The counties of Dallas and Ellis shall elect one senator; Ellis to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fourteenth District&#8212;The counties of Navarro, Limestone and Freestone shall elect one senator; Limestone to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fifteenth District&#8212;Leon, Robertson and Brazos counties shall elect one senator; Robertson to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixteenth District&#8212;Grimes, Madison, Walker and Trinity counties shall elect one senator; Walker to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventeenth District&#8212;Waller, Fort Bend and Wharton counties shall elect one senator; Waller to be returning county.</p>
<p>Eighteenth District&#8212;The counties of Harris and Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery shall elect one senator; Harris to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Nineteenth District&#8212;The counties of Galveston, Brazoria and Matagorda shall elect one senator; Galveston to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twentieth District&#8212;Austin, Washington and Burleson counties shall elect one senator; Washington to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-first District&#8212;The counties of Falls, Milam and Bell shall elect one senator; and Milam shall be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-second District&#8212;The counties of Johnson, Hill and McLennan shall elect one senator; McLennan to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-third District&#8212;The counties of Tarrant, Parker, Wise, Montague, Clay, Jack and Young, with the unorgan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized counties west of them, shall elect one senator; Tarrant to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fourth District&#8212;The counties of Coryell, Bosque, Hamilton, Brown, Coleman, Comanche, Erath, Somerville, Hood, Palo Pinto, Eastland and Shackleford, with the un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />organized counties of Runnels, Taylor, Calahan, Jones and Stephens, shall elect one senator; Comanche to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fifth District&#8212;The counties of Travis, William<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Burnet and Lampasas shall elect one senator; William<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-sixth District&#8212;The counties of Fayette, Bastrop and Lee shall elect one senator; Fayette to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-seventh District&#8212;The counties of Colorado, Lava<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="756" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>ca and Gonzales shall elect one senator; Lavaca to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-eighth District&#8212;The counties of Calhoun, Vic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toria, De Witt, Aransas, Refugio, Bee, Goliad, Karnes, Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Jackson and Atascosa shall elect one senator; Victoria to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-ninth District&#8212;The counties of Cameron, Hi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dalgo, Starr, Zapata, Webb, Maverick, Kinney, Uvalde, Me<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dina, Nueces, San Patricio, Live Oak and Frio, with the unorganized counties of Duval, Encinal, McMullen, LaSalle, Dimmitt and Zavala, shall elect one senator; Nueces to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirtieth District&#8212;The counties of Bexar, Comal, Ban<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dera, Kendall, Kerr, Gillespie, Mason, Menard, Tom Green, Pecos, Presidio and El Paso, with the unorganized counties of Concho, Kimball, Edwards and Crockett, shall elect one senator; Bexar to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-first District&#8212;The counties of Guadalupe, Cald<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />well, Hays, Blanco, Llano and San Saba, with the unor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized county of McCulloch, shall elect one senator; Hays to be the returning county.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Representative Districts.</head>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained, That until such appor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tionment after the census of 1880, representatives shall be elected as follows:</p>
<p>First District&#8212;The counties of Liberty, Hardin, Jefferson and Chambers shall elect one representative; Liberty to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Second District&#8212;The comities of San Jacinto, Polk and Tyler shall elect one representative; Tyler to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Third District&#8212;The counties of Jasper, Newton and Or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ange shall elect one representative; Jasper to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Fourth District&#8212;The counties of San Augustine and Sabine shall elect one representative; San Augustine to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fifth District&#8212;The county of Houston shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Sixth District&#8212;The counties of Nacogdoches and Angelina shall elect one representative; Nacogdoches to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Seventh District&#8212;The county of Rusk shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Eighth District&#8212;The counties of Panola and Shelby shall<pb n="757" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>elect one representative; Panola to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Ninth District&#8212;The counties of Rusk, Panola and Shelby shall elect one representative; Panola to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Tenth District&#8212;The county of Harrison shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Eleventh District&#8212;The counties of Marion, Cass, Bowie and Morris shall elect three representatives; Cass to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twelfth District&#8212;The county of Red River shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Thirteenth District&#8212;The counties of Titus and Franklin shall elect one representative; Titus to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fourteenth District&#8212;The county of Hopkins shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifteenth District&#8212;The county of Smith shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Sixteenth District&#8212;The counties of Smith and Gregg shall elect one representative; Smith to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventeenth District&#8212;The counties of Camp and Upshur shall elect one representative; Upshur to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Eighteenth District&#8212;The county of Lamar shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Nineteenth District&#8212;The county of Fannin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twentieth District&#8212;The counties of Lamar, Fannin and Delta shall elect one representative; Lamar to be the return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county.</p>
<p>Twenty-first District&#8212;The counties of Hunt and Rock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wall shall elect one representative; Hunt to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-second District&#8212;The counties of Kaufman, Raines, Wood and Van Zandt shall elect two representatives; Kaufman to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Twenty-third District&#8212;The county of Henderson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twenty-fourth District&#8212;The county of Anderson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twenty-fifth District&#8212;The county of Cherokee shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twenty-sixth District&#8212;The county of Leon shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twenty-seventh District&#8212;The county of Robertson shall elect two representatives.</p>
<pb n="758" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Twenty-eighth District&#8212;The county of Brazos shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Twenty-ninth District&#8212;The county of Grimes shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Thirtieth District&#8212;The counties of Grimes and Madison shall elect one representative; Grimes to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-first District&#8212;The counties of Walker and Trinity shall elect one representative; Walker to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-second District&#8212;The county of Montgomery shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Thirty-third District&#8212;Harris county shall elect two rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives.</p>
<p>Thirty-fourth District&#8212;The counties of Harris and Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery shall elect one representative; Harris to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-fifth District&#8212;Galveston county shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Thirty-sixth District&#8212;The counties of Brazoria, Galveston and Matagorda shall elect one representative; Galveston to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-seventh District&#8212;The counties of Wharton, Fort Bend and Waller shall elect two representatives; Waller to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Thirty-eighth District&#8212;Austin county shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Thirty-ninth District&#8212;Washington county shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fortieth District&#8212;Washington and Burleson counties shall elect one representative; Burleson to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Forty-first District&#8212;The counties of Falls, Milam and Bell shall elect three representatives; Bell to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Forty-second District&#8212;The county of Limestone shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Forty-third District&#8212;The county of Freestone shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Forty-fourth District&#8212;The county of Navarro shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Forty-fifth District&#8212;The county of Ellis shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Forty-sixth District&#8212;The county of Dallas shall elect two representatives.</p>
<pb n="759" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Forty-seventh District&#8212;The county of Collin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Forty-eighth District&#8212;The county of Grayson shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Forty-ninth District&#8212;The counties of Grayson and Collin shall elect one representative; Grayson to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fiftieth District&#8212;The county of Cooke shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Fifty-first District&#8212;The county of Denton shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifty-second District&#8212;The counties of Clay, Montague and Wise, with the unorganized counties west of Clay, shall elect one representative; Wise to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fifty-third District&#8212;The county of Tarrant shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifty-fourth District&#8212;The counties of Parker, Jack and Young, with the unorganized counties west of them, shall elect one representative; Parker to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fifty-fifth District&#8212;The county of Johnson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifty-sixth District&#8212;The county of Hill shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifty-seventh District&#8212;The county of McLennan shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Fifty-eighth District&#8212;The counties of Jackson, Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />houn, Victoria, DeWitt, Aransas, Refugio, Bee and Goliad shall elect two representatives; Victoria to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Fifty-ninth District&#8212;The counties of Colorado and Lavaca shall elect two representatives; Lavaca to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixtieth District&#8212;The county of Gonzales shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Sixty-first District&#8212;The county of Fayette shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Sixty-second District&#8212;The county of Bastrop shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Sixty-third District&#8212;The counties of Fayette and Lee shall elect one representative; Fayette to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixty-fourth District&#8212;The counties of Caldwell, Guada<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lupe and Hays shall elect two representatives; Hays to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixty-fifth District&#8212;Travis county shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<pb n="760" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Sixty-sixth District&#8212;Travis and Blanco counties shall elect one representative; Travis to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sixty-seventh District&#8212;Williamson and Lampasas coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties shall elect one representative; Williamson to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Sixty-eighth District&#8212;The counties of Coryell, Hamil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Brown and Coleman, and the unorganized county of Runnels, shall elect one representative; Coryell to be the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning county.</p>
<p>Sixty-ninth District&#8212;The counties of Bosque, Somerville and Hood shall elect one representative; Bosque to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventieth District&#8212;The counties of Erath, Comanche, Palo Pinto, Eastland and Shackelford, with the unorganized counties of Stephens, Jones, Callahan and Taylor, shall elect one representative; Comanche to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-first District&#8212;The county of Bexar shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Seventy-second District&#8212;The counties of Bexar and Co<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mal shall elect one representative; Bexar to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-third District&#8212;The counties of Uvalde, Me<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dina, Bandera, Kendall, Kerr, Gillespie, Mason and Menard, with the unorganized counties of Edwards and Kimble, shall elect one representative; Gillespie to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-fourth District&#8212;The counties of Llano, Burnet, San Saba, McCulloch and Concho shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive; San Saha to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-fifth District&#8212;The counties of El Paso, Presidio, Pecos, Tom Green and Crockett shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive; El Paso to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-sixth District&#8212;The counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Webb and Zapata shall elect one representative; Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eron to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-seventh District&#8212;The counties of Nueces, Frio, Maverick and Kinney, with the unorganized counties of Du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />val, Encinal, McMullen, Dimmitt, LaSalle and Zavala, shall elect one representative; Nueces to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-eighth District&#8212;The counties of San Patricio, Live Oak, Karnes, Wilson and Atascosa shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative; Karnes to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Seventy-ninth District&#8212;The counties of Cherokee, Rusk, Panola, Shelby and Harrison, shall elect one representative; Rusk to be the returning county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further ordained, That, for all purposes con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nected with the first election provided for by this convention,<pb n="761" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>this ordinance shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and should the Constitution be ratified by the people, this ordinance shall be and remain in force until the first apportionment after the census of 1880; but should the Constitution be rejected by the people, this ordinance shall thereafter be and remain of no force and effect.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. B. PICKETT, <lb/>President of the Convention.</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To Divide the State of Texas into Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the people of the State of Texas, in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention assembled, that until otherwise provided by law, the State of Texas shall be divided into twenty-six Judicial Districts, as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 1. The First District shall be composed of the counties of Jefferson, Chambers, Liberty, Hardin, Polk, Ty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, Jasper, Newton, Orange and San Jacinto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Second District shall be composed of the counties of Harrison, Rusk, Panola, Shelby and Sabine.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Third District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of San Augustine, Nacogdoches, Cherokee, Houston and Anderson.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The Fourth District shall be composed of the counties of Grimes, Walker, Madison, Leon, Trinity and An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gelina.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Fifth District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Marion, Cass, Bowie, Titus, Morris, Franklin and Camp.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Sixth District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Red River, Lamar, Fannin and Grayson.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Seventh District shall be composed of the counties of Gregg, Smith, Upshur, Wood, Raines, Van Zandt and Henderson.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The Eighth District shall be composed of the counties of Hunt, Hopkins, Collin, Rockwall, Kaufman and Delta.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The Ninth District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Brazos, Robertson, Burleson and Milam.</p>
<pb n="762" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Sec. 10. The Tenth District shall be composed of the counties of Cooke, Denton, Montague, Wise, Clay, Parker, Tarrant, and the unorganized counties of Archer, Wichita, Baylor, Wilbarger, Knox, Hardeman, Greer and Wegeforth.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The Eleventh District shall be composed of the counties of Dallas and Ellis.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. The Twelfth District shall be composed of the counties of Hood, Coryell, Hamilton, Comanche, Brown, Coleman, Shackelford, Palo Pinto, Eastland, Erath, Somerville, Jack, Young, and the unorganized counties of Jones, Taylor, Runnels, Callahan, Stephens, Haskell and Throckmorton.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The Thirteenth District shall be composed of the counties of Hill, Navarro, Limestone, Bosque, Johnson and Freestone.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. The Fourteenth District shall be composed of the counties of McLennan, Bell and Falls.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The Fifteenth District shall be composed of the counties of Austin, Fayette, Bastrop, Caldwell, Hays and Blanco.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. The Sixteenth District shall be composed of the counties of Washington, Lee, Travis and Williamson.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The Seventeenth District shall be composed of the counties of Burnet, Lampasas, San Saba, Llano, Mason, Menard, Gillespie, and the unorganized counties of Concho, McCulloch and Kimble.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. The Eighteenth District shall be composed of the counties of Waller, Wharton, Fort Bend, Brazoria, Matagorda and Jackson.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. The Ninteenth District shall be composed of the counties of Colorado, Lavaca, Gonzales, Guadalupe and Wilson.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. The Twentieth District shall be composed of the counties of El Paso, Presidio, Tom Green, Pecos and Crockett.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. The Twenty-first District shall be composed of the counties of Harris and Montgomery.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. The Twenty-second District shall be composed of the counties of Comal, Bexar and Atascosa.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. The Twenty-third District shall be composed of the counties of DeWitt, Victoria, Calhoun, Refugio, Goli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ad, Bee, Aransas, San Patricio, Karnes, Live Oak and Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Mullen.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. The twenty-fourth District shall be composed of the counties of Kendall, Kerr, Bandera, Medina, Frio,<pb n="763" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>Uvalde, Zavalla, Kinney, Maverick, Dimmit, LaSalle, Ed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wards and Dawson.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. The Twenty-fifth District shall be composed of the counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Webb, En<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinal, Nueces and Duval.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. The Twenty-sixth District shall be composed of the county of Galveston.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. Be it further ordained, That for all pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses connected with the first election provided for by this Convention, this ordinance shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage; and should the Constitution be ratified by the people, this ordinance shall be and remain in force until otherwise changed by the Legislature of this State; but should the Constitution be rejected by the people, this ordinance shall thereafter be of no force or effect.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. B. PICKETT, <lb/>President of the Convention.</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Fixing the terms of the District Courts of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the people of Texas in Convention assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bled, that until otherwise provided by law, the terms of the Districts Courts of the several judicial districts shall be as hereinafter prescribed:</p>
<p>Section 1. That the District Courts of the First Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Chambers, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Liberty, on the first Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of San Jacinto, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Polk, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Tyler, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<pb n="764" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>In the county of Jasper, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Newton, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Orange, on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Jefferson, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hardin, on the nineteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts of the Second Judicial District be holden on the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Sabine, on the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Shelby, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Panola, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Rusk, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion six weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Harrison, on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the District Courts of the Third Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of San Augustine, on the first Mondays in September and February, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Nacogdoches, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Cherokee, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Houston, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in September, and continue in session five weeks; and on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in February, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<pb n="765" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>In the county of Anderson, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in September, and on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the District Courts of the Fourth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Angelina, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Trinity, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Walker, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Grimes, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Madison, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Leon, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the District Courts of the Fifth Judicial District shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Cass, on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bowie, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Morris, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Titus, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Franklin, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Camp, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Marion, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue<pb n="766" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>in session eight weeks or until the business of the term can be disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the District Courts of the Sixth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Grayson, on the first Mondays in Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary and July, and may continue in session seven weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Fannin, on the seventh Monday after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Lamar, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Red River, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the District Courts of the Seventh Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Smith, on the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Henderson, on the sixth Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Van Zandt, on the eighth Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Rains, on the eleventh Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Wood, on the twelfth Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Upshur, on the fifteenth Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Gregg, on the eighteenth Mondays after the second Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the District Courts of the Eighth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Hunt; on the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Delta, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hopkins, on the fifth Mondays after the<pb n="767" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Kaufman, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Rockwall, on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Collin, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion six weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the District Courts of the Ninth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Brazos on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Burleson, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Milam, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Robertson on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the District Courts of the Tenth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Cooke, on the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Denton, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Tarrant, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Parker, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Wise on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Clay, on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Montague, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session until business is disposed of.</p>
<pb n="768" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. That the District Courts of the Eleventh Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Ellis, on the second Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session five weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Dallas, on the fifth Mondays after the second Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the District Courts of the Twelfth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Coryell on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hamilton on the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Comanche on the second Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Brown, on the fourth Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Coleman, on the second Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Shackleford, on the third Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Young, on the fourth Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Jack, on the first Mondays in June and December, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Palo Pinto, on the second Mondays of June and December, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hood, on the third Mondays in June and December, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Somerville, on the second Mondays in July and January, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Erath, on the third Mondays in July and January, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Eastland, on the first Mondays in Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust and February, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>For judicial purposes Runnels shall be attached to Cole<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man; Taylor and Callahan to Eastland; Jones, Haskell, Throckmorton and Stephens to Shackelford.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the District Courts of the Thirteenth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Limestone, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<pb n="769" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>In the county of Freestone, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Navarro, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hill, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Johnson, on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bosque, on the nineteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the District Courts of the Fourteenth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Falls, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bell, on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of McLennan, on the first Mondays in May and November, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the District Courts of the Fifteenth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Blanco, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hays, on the first Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Caldwell, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bastrop, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Fayette, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Austin, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the District Courts of the Sixteenth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="770" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>cial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Washington, on the first Mondays in Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary and July, and may continue in session eight weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Lee, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Williamson, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Travis, on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the District Courts of the Seventeenth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Burnet, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Lampasas, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of San Saba, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Menard, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Mason, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Llano, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Gillespie, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>The counties of Concho and Kimball are attached to Me<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nard county for judicial purposes, and the county of Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Culloch is attached for judicial purposes to the county of San Saba.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the District Courts of the Eighteenth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Waller, on the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Fort Bend, on the third Mondays after<pb n="771" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Wharton, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Jackson, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Matagorda, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Brazoria, on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That the District Courts of the Nineteenth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Lavaca, on the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Colorado, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Gonzales, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session five weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Guadalupe, on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Wilson, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That the District Courts of the Twentieth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of El Paso, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Presidio, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Pecos, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Tom Green, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks.</p>
<pb n="772" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>The county of Crockett is attached to Tom Green county for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That the District Courts of the Twenty-first Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Montgomery, on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Harris, on the second Mondays in March and October, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That the District Courts of the Twenty-second Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Comal, on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Atascosa, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bexar, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That the District Courts of the Twenty-third Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of DeWitt, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Victoria, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Calhoun, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Refugio, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Aransas, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of San Patricio, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Goliad, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bee, on the thirteenth Mondays after the<pb n="773" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Live Oak, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Karnes, on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>McMullen county is attached to Live Oak county for judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That the District Courts of the Twenty-fourth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Kendall, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Kerr on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Bandera, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Medina, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Frio, on the sixth Mondays after the first. Mondays in March and September, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Uvalde, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Kinney, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Maverick, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>The unorganized counties of Dimmitt and Zavalla are attached, for judicial purposes, to the county of Maverick; Edwards county is attached, for judicial purposes, to Kerr county, and LaSalle county to Frio county.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That the District Courts of the Twenty-fifth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Cameron, on the third Mondays in Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary and August, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hidalgo, on the fourth Mondays after<pb n="774" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>the third Mondays in February and August, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Starr, on the fifth Mondays after the third Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Zapata, on the sixth Mondays after the third Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Webb, on the seventh Mondays after the third Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Nueces, on the tenth Mondays after the third Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Encinal county is attached, for judicial purposes, to Webb county, and Duval county to the county of Nueces.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That the District Courts of the Twenty-sixth Judicial District be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Galveston, on the first Mondays in Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, April, June, October and December, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. All writs and process, civil and criminal, here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore issued by or from the District Courts, in the several counties of this State, and made returnable to the former terms of said courts, as said terms are now fixed by law, shall be returnable to the next ensuing terms of said District Courts in each county, as they are prescribed in this Ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance; and all such writs and process that may be issued by or from said courts at any time within five days next before the holding of the next ensuing terms of said courts, as pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed herein, are hereby made returnable to said terms re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively; and all such writs and process hereinbefore men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned are hereby legalized and validated, to all intents and purposes, as if the same had been made returnable to the term or terms of said court, as the terms thereof are herein prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That in case where the time has partly elapsed for holding any term of the District Court, as herein pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed, at the time of the qualification of the District Judge of said District, then said Judge shall proceed to hold said court for the remainder of said term.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. B. PICKETT, <lb/>President of the Convention.</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="775" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Submitting the new Constitution to a vote of the people, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion assembled, That the new Constitution, framed by this Convention, shall be submitted to the electors of this State at an election, which shall be held throughout the State on the third Tuesday in February, A. D. 1876, for their ratifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation or rejection. Those electors in favor of ratification shall have written or printed on their ballots, &#8220;For the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.&#8221; Those electors opposed to the ratification shall have written or printed on their ballots, &#8220;Against the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.&#8221; If a majority of all the votes cast at said election, and returned to the Secretary of State, shall be in favor of ratification, the Governor shall, within five days next suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding the return day, issue his proclamation declaring the fact, and then the new Constitution shall, on the third Tues<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in April, A. D. 1876, become, and thereafter be, the or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganic and fundamental law of the State. If, however, a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of all the votes so cast and returned be against ratifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, then the new Constitution shall have and be of no effect whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further, ordained, That at the same time there shall be a general election held throughout the State for all State, district, county and precinct officers, created and made elective by the new Constitution. The election, as far as practicable, shall be held and conducted as now provided by law; but no registration of voters shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired, and every elector shall vote in the precinct of his resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence; provided, that electors residing in unorganized coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties may vote in any precinct of the county to which their respective counties are attached for judicial purposes. The qualifications of electors shall be as defined in the article regulating suffrage in the new Constitution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further ordained, That the county courts now existing shall meet at their respective county seats within twenty days after the adjournment of this Convention, or as soon thereafter as practicable, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />divide their respective counties into the number of pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cincts provided for by the new Constitution and make immediate proclamation thereof for the information of the people. Said courts shall establish at least one voting place in each precinct, and where deemed necessary for public con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="776" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>venience, they shall establish two or more voting places in any precinct.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further ordained, That the returns of said election shall be made as now provided by law, to the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding justice of each county, and to the returning officer of each returning county named in the ordinance apportioning the State into senatorial and representative districts, passed by this Convention, as is now required by law, and to the Secretary of State where by law it is now required. In all cases the returns shall be made, opened, counted, and the result recorded and declared by the proper officers as is pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by existing laws, and the returns of the election of all judges shall be made by the presiding justice of each county to the Secretary, of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. If the new Constitution shall be ratified by the people, then the county judges, county attorneys, and other county officers created by the new Constitution shall, until otherwise provided, receive such fees as were allowed by the Constitution and laws of 1866.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further ordained, That in case the new Constitution shall be ratified at said election, the Senators and Representatives then elected shall assemble as the Fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature, at the seat of government, on the third Tuesday in April, A. D. 1876.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further ordained, That after the first elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion herein provided for, until otherwise prescribed by law, the regular biennial elections of this State, for State, district, county and precinct officers, after the year 1876, shall be held on the Tuesday next after the first Monday in Novem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, every second year, commencing with November, 1878. All officers elected at the election herein provided for, shall hold their offices as though they had been elected in No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember, 1876, whether the tenure of their offices, by the new Constitution, be for two, four or six years.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further ordained, That all judicial, dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, county and precinct officers elected in accordance with the provisions of this ordinance shall be installed in office on the third Tuesday in April, A. D. 1876; provided, that persons, so elected who may be prevented from qual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ifying by reason of illness or absence, shall have twenty addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional days in which to do so. The Governor and all State officers not named before in this section, shall be installed on the first Tuesday after the assemblage of the Legislature elected as herein provided. As each newly elected officer may be qualified, his predecessor, if any, shall cease his func<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and deliver to his successor all books, papers, archives<pb n="777" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>and records, and all property of whatever nature or kind, pertaining to his office or in his possession or charge.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. There shall be no session of the Legislature in January, 1876, unless specially called by the Governor, nor except under the provisions of the new Constitution and this ordinance, or under the ordinance of this Convention post<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poning the election of December, 1875.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this ordinance shall take effect and be in full force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. B. PICKETT, <lb/>President of the Convention.</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an Ordinance to provide for submitting the Constitution to a vote of the people, and for a general elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion under its provisions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas in Convention assembled, That all returns of the election to be held on the third Tuesday in February, 1876, under the provisions of the ordinance to which this is supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentary, shall be made to the presiding justice of each county, by the proper election officers, on or before the Saturday next succeeding the said day of election, on which day the presiding justice, or, in his absence, or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fusal to act, the district clerk, shall open, compare and record the votes for all officers, and on the ratification or rejection of the Constitution, as is provided for other elections by law. The presiding justice, or district clerk, as the case may be, shall immediately make return of the vote for or against the Constitution, for all State officers, all judicial officers, and for district attorneys in the districts in which they are to be chosen. The returns for Governor and other State officers shall be made separately, and address<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed to the speaker of the House of Representatives, to the care of the Secretary of State. The returns for and against the Constitution, for judges of the supreme, appellate and district courts, and for district attorneys, shall be addressed to the Secretary of State. On the third Tuesday in March, the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, Secretary of State and Attorney General shall open, count, record and declare the result in the returns for and<pb n="778" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>against the Constitution, for supreme, appellate and district judges, and for district attorneys; whereupon, within five days, the Governor shall make proclamation of the result, as to the ratification or rejection of the Constitution, and if the Constitution be ratified, issue certificates of election to the persons who may be chosen, to the respective judicial district offices herein referred to.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. B. PICKETT, <lb/>President of the Convention</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">AN ORDINANCE.</head>
<p>Be it ordained by the people of Texas, in Convention assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bled, That the Governor be authorized and requested, imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately upon the adjournment of this Convention, to issue his proclamation for the election contemplated by &#8220;an ordinance submitting the new Constitution to a vote of the people, and for other purposes,&#8221; passed by this Convention on the twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />second of November, A. D. 1875, and an ordinance supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental thereto, passed on the twenty-third day of November, 1875; and that said election be holden in the manner pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in said ordinance and supplement, and by such of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers as are authorized by law to hold general elections under existing laws.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 23, 1875</date>.</dateline>
<signed>E. B. PICKET, President of the Convention.</signed>
<signed>Attest: LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Resolved, That George Flournoy, W. P. Ballinger and W. H. Stewart, members of this Convention, be and they are hereby appointed a committee to supervise the printing of the Constitution, and see that the work is done in accordance with the enrolled copy.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted <date>November 23, 1875</date>.</dateline>
<signed>LEIGH CHALMERS, <lb/>Secretary of the Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
