<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="265" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="263" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main"><b>SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>SESSION OF THE FOURTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>BEGUN AND HELD <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</b></head>
<byline>JANUARY 13, 1874</byline>
<byline>HOUSTON 1874</byline>
<pb n="266" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="264" />
<pb n="267" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub"><b>SPECIAL LAWS OF TEXAS.</b></head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to re-enact an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize the Police Court of Leon County to Levy and Collect a Special Tax to Build a Jail, and to validate the action of said Court under said Law,&#8221; and to cause the same to be pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished as one of the Laws of the Thirteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, whereas House bill No. 182, originating in the House of Representatives, entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize the Police court of Leon county to levy and collect a special tax to build a jail, and which said bill, under all of the forms of law, passed the Thirteenth Legislature of the State of Texas, and was on the second day of June, A. D. 1873, at 10:25 o&#8217;clock a. m., presented to his Excellency the Governor of the State for his approval, and the said Governor having failed to approve the same, or return the same to the House of Representatives, where it originated, with his objections to the same, said act did, under the constitution, become a law, which said act is in words and figures as follows: &#8220;An Act to authorize the police court of Leon county to levy and collect a special tax to build a jail:&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Police Court of the county of Leon is hereby authorized to levy a special tax of not more than one-third of one per cent. ad valorem on each one hundred dollars worth of the value of the taxable property in said county, also a tax of not more than fifty cents on each poll in said county; also a tax of not more than one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenth of the tax levied and collected by the State for occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation or license upon any trade or profession taxed by the State in said county; and said court is authorized to levy<pb n="268" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said special tax for the years A. D. 1873, A. D. 1874, and A. D. 1875, or any or either of said years as they may deem necessary; and that the taxes herein provided shall be assessed and collected as any other State or county taxes under the general tax laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the money arising from taxes under the first section of this act shall only be expended and appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated by said police court for the purpose of purchasing a lot of land on which to erect a jail-house for said county, and for the erection of a suitable house for said jail, and in connection with said jail room or rooms for a jailor, and for the proper furnishing of said jail and jailor&#8217;s rooms, and to properly enclose said jail lot, and such other matters as may be deemed necessary by said court in connection with said jail.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That after the payment by said court of all de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mands and expenses arising under the second section of this act, if any balance of said funds is left in the county treasury, the court may appropriate such balance to repairs for the courthouse of the county, or for enclosing with a proper fence the courthouse yard.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The taxes imposed under the first section of this act shall only be payable and collectable in money, and shall be payable into the county treasury in money, and shall only be paid out by the county treasurer on draft of the court, specially stating that it is in liquidation of debt on jail fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no county officer shall have any interest, either directly or indirectly in any contract for building of said county jail or furnishing materials for same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage.</p>
<p>Therefore, To remove any doubt as to the validity of said act, or as to the action of the county or police court of said county under it, and to require the publication of said act among the special laws of the Thirteenth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of the State of Texas, said afore recited law is hereby re-enacted and validated, and the action of the county court of Leon county, under the provisions of the same, is hereby validated and legalized; and that said act be pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by the Governor as one of the laws of the Thirteenth Legislature, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 23,1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="269" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to incorporate the City of Browns<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville, approved February 7, A. D. 1853.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the ninth section of an act to incorporate the city of Brownsville, approved February 7, A. D. 1853, be amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;Section 9. That an election for mayor and nine aldermen shall be held in the different wards of said city on the first Tuesday of October, A. D. 1874, and annually thereafter. The mayor shall give twenty days notice of said elections, and in case of vacancy in the office of mayor, or of his neglect or refusal to order said election, the same may be ordered by a majority of the aldermen. In case of vacancy by death, resignation or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, the vacancy or vacancies shall be filled by election, ten days notice of which shall be given; and in case of vacancy in the office of mayor, the aldermen shall elect one of their own body to act as mayor until the next annual election. The city council shall have power to pass any ordinance regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating the registration of voters and holding elections, which shall not contravene the provisions of this charter or any gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral law of this State. The election of officers under this act shall be held in the different wards of said city. Judges of election shall be appointed by the board of aldermen. They shall take an oath to faithfully and impartially discharge their duties; they shall open the polls at nine o&#8217;clock a. m., and close them at sunset, when they shall forthwith proceed to ascertain and certify the result of the election, the returns of which shall be made to the city council within three days thereafter; the city council, upon receipt of said re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns, shall open and examine the same, and give certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates of election to those found duly elected. The parties receiving said certificates of election shall qualify and be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stalled in office on the first Tuesday after election.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 23, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="270" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to consolidate in one Act and amend the several Acts incorporating the City of Houston, in Harris County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the inhabitants of the city of Houston shall be a body corporate by the name of the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston, and by that name they shall be known in law, and shall be capable of suing and being sued, and defending in all courts and in all actions and matters whatever; may have a common seal, and may alter and change the same at pleasure; may hold and convey any estate, real and personal, for the use of said corporation; provided, that such real estate be within the corporate limits of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bounds and limits of said corporation shall be three miles square, to be run with the cardinal points of the compass, of which the center of the court-house square, in the city of Houston, shall be the center.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the city council may divide the city into a convenient number of wards, not exceeding eight, and define and establish the boundaries thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the administration of the business affairs of said corporation shall be conducted by a mayor and board of aldermen who shall compose the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be a qualified voter at any election for officers of said corporation unless he possesses the qualifications of an elector under the laws of the State, and has resided within the corporate limits of the city sixty days next preceding the election, and is at the time of the election a registered voter therein.</p>
<p>See. 6. That the mayor shall be elected by the quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied voters of the city and shall hold his office for the term of two years, and until his successor is elected and quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied. He shall be a conservator of the peace throughout the city. He shall have power, by and with the consent of the city council, to appoint any number of policemen on any special occasion, that he may deem necessary to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serve the peace of the city, and to discharge the same at pleasure; he shall have power in case of necessity to call out the militia, or any military company in the city, to aid in the suppression of any riot or public disturbance; he<pb n="271" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be active and vigilant in enforcing all laws and ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances for the government of the city, and he shall cause all the subordinate officers to be dealt with promptly for any neglect or violation of duty. He shall preside at all meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of the city council when present, and in case of a tie vote in the board of aldermen he shall give the casting vote. He shall have the power to veto any resolution, by-law or ordinance passed by the council, and when vetoed the same shall be inoperative, unless it shall be reconsidered at a sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequent meeting, and passed by the votes of two-thirds of the aldermen present, taken by &#8220;yeas and nays&#8221; and entered upon the journals of the council. He shall have power to hold the recorder&#8217;s court, in case of the temporary absence or illness of the recorder, and it shall be his duty to do so. He shall have power to administer oaths and affirmations. He shall have and exercise such powers and authority as may be conferred by the city council not inconsistent with the general purposes and provisions of this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That each ward in the city shall be represented in the city council by two aldermen elected by the quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied voters of each ward, who shall vote only in their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective wards. They shall be residents of the ward rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resented by them, and shall be qualified electors of the city at the first election for officers of the city to be held under this charter; two aldermen shall be elected from each ward, one of whom shall hold the office for the term of one year, and one for the term of two years; and immediately after the organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation of the board of aldermen so elected, the aldermen from each ward shall determine by lots which shall hold the term of two years, and annually thereafter one alderman shall be elected from each ward, who shall hold the office for the term of two years, and until his successor shall be elected and quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That regular meetings of the city council shall be held in the council chamber, at least once in each month, at such times as may be fixed by resolution of the board, and the mayor, of his own motion, may call special meetings for the transaction of special business, by written notice served personally upon each member of the board, or left at his usual place of abode; any three members of the board may in like manner call special meetings of the council; but no special meetings shall be called except in cases of urgent necessity, and the written notices served<pb n="272" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>upon the members of the board shall state the object and purpose for which the council is convened; and no other business shall be transacted at such special meetings except that for which the meeting is called. General business shall only be transacted at the regular meetings. The city council may adjourn from day to day until the business properly coming before it is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That a majority of the whole number of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men elected and qualified shall be required to constitute a quorum for the transaction of business; but any four alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men may convene and compel the attendance of absent mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers on any day of regular meetings.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the city council shall adopt rules and regulations for the government of the council in its pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings, and the order for the transaction of business be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore it. It shall be the judge of the qualifications and elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the members of the council, including the mayor. It may punish members or other persons during the sittings of the council for disorderly conduct, to the extent that it may fine and imprison by its by-laws and ordinances; and with the affirmative vote of two-thirds of the whole number of aldermen elected and qualified, the council may remove any officer of the city, from his office, for any conduct or offense which, in the opinion of the council, expressed by the two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote as aforesaid, shall render him unfit to hold his office; but no officer shall be removed until he shall have had the opportunity of being heard by himself, or counsel, or both.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the meeting of the council shall be held with open doors, except when by a vote of two-thirds of the members present it may be deemed expedient upon a special question to deliberate with closed doors.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That whenever it shall be necessary so to do, the board of aldermen shall by ballot elect a member of their own body to act for a designated period as mayor pro tem., who, for the time, shall have and exercise all the powers and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority of the mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That in case of a vacancy occurring in any office elective by the qualified voters of the city, the city council shall order an election to fill the vacancy upon giving ten days notice thereof, which election shall be held and conduc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted in the same manner, and under the same rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions prescribed for the holding of general elections in the city.</p>
<pb n="273" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 14. That there shall be elected by the board of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men as soon after its organization as practicable, a city re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder, the secretary and treasurer, the city marshal, the assessor and collector, the city attorney, the street commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner, and the city sexton, who shall hold office for the term of one year, and until their successors are elected and quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied; and the election of said officers named in this section may be remitted to the voters of the city at any general elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion after the first year.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the city recorder shall have jurisdiction within the limits of the corporation, with power to hear and determine all cases of violation of the ordinances of the city council, which shall be prosecuted in the name and in behalf of &#8220;the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton,&#8221; and for the proper exercise of such jurisdiction, the recorder shall have power and authority to issue process; to preserve order and punish for contempts committed in the presence of his court; to administer oaths and affirmations; to summon witnesses, either in the city or from any part of Harris county, and compel their attendance, but process to be executed beyond the city limits shall be directed to and executed by the sheriff or some constable for the county; to summon jurors and compel their attendance; the recorder&#8217;s court shall be opened daily and the accused shall have a speedy trial, the law of the State regulating the practice and procedure in the courts of justices of the peace, shall be the rule for the practice and procedure in the recorder&#8217;s court. In the absence, sickness or inability of the recorder to act and hold his court, the recorder&#8217;s court may be held by the acting mayor at the time; and in such case the acting mayor shall have the same jurisdiction, powers and authority as the recorder. The recorder in addition to his salary, and his min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isterial officers executing his process, shall have the same fees as justices of the peace have for similar services. He shall make report to the council from time to time as required, and shall do and perform such duties properly appertaining to the office of recorder as may be prescribed by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the secretary and treasurer shall attend the city council at its meetings; he shall have the custody of all the laws and ordinances of the city; he shall have the custody of the common seal of the corporation, and shall only affix the same to the obligations of the city by<pb n="274" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>order of the city council; he shall keep a regular and correct journal of the proceedings of the council in well bound rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ord books; he shall be the treasurer and have the custody of all moneys and valuable papers, records and archives of the city; he shall receive all moneys and revenues coming into the city treasury and pay the same out by order of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil; he shall keep the money and funds of the city on deposit in some bank in the city of Houston; he shall keep the ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts of the city in well bound books, and the books and records of his office shall be open to the inspection of any citizen upon request, at any reasonable and proper time. He shall prepare and publish in one or more newspapers printed in the city of Houston an accurate and detailed statement and account of the receipts and disbursements of the revenues of the city; the outstanding obligations and liabilities of the city, and the condition of the city treasury, which statement shall be prepared and made up the first Monday of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember of each year, and published on or before the fifteenth day of December; and it shall be the duty of the city council to require this statement so to be made and published; and should the said statement not be made in the manner and at the time provided, the secretary and treasurer shall be liable to a fine of one thousand dollars, to be recovered in the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court of Harris county at the suit of the city attorney, for and in behalf of &#8220;the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston,&#8221; and the securities of the city secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary and treasurer, on his official bond, shall be liable for the amount of such fine; and judgment nisi shall be entered against them at the same time with the principal, to be made final upon a return of a writ of scire facias; and the city council may prescribe such other duties to be performed by the secretary and treasurer, concerning the administration of his office, as may be deemed advisable.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the city marshal shall be the chief police officer of the city under the mayor; he shall attend all regular and special meetings of the council; he shall at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend upon the recorder&#8217;s court, and shall promptly exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute and return all process issued from said court; he shall be active in quelling riots, disorders and disturbances of the peace within the limits of said city, and shall take in custody all persons so offending against the peace of the community; he shall arrest all offenders against the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="275" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>nances of the city for offenses committed in his presence, and shall have authority to take bail for their appearance before the recorder, and in default of giving which he shall commit them to the city prison for safe keeping until they can be brought before the recorder for trial; he shall have authority to appoint one deputy, for whose acts and conduct he shall be responsible, and such deputy shall have all the power and authority of the marshal; he shall perform such other duties and shall be invested with such other powers, rights and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority as the city council may by ordinance confer, not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consistent with the Constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the assessor and collector shall assess and collect the licenses and taxes levied and imposed by the city council, and shall pay the same over to the secretary and treasurer weekly on the Saturday of each week, taking dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate receipts therefor, one of which he shall retain, and the other he shall return to the council or the proper committee appointed by the council to receive the same, with his report in detail showing the several amounts received and by whom paid, which report shall be made to the first meeting of the council in each month; he shall be governed by the rules and regulations hereinafter prescribed in relation to the assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and collection of the licenses and taxes imposed by the city council, and shall do and perform such other acts and duties concerning the administration of his office as may be prescribed by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That the city attorney shall in person or by dep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uty appear and prosecute all cases in the recorder&#8217;s court arising under the ordinances of the city; he shall, upon the request of the mayor or board of aldermen, attend the meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of the council, to give his advice and counsel, and shall give his opinion verbally or in writing, as requested, upon all legal questions affecting the rights and interests of the city which may arise under the city government; he shall, when requested, draw up or revise any ordinance of the city; he shall represent the city in the prosecution or defense of any and all actions or suits in any and all courts wherein its rights or interests are involved; he shall draw up all contracts for the city, and prepare all official bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That the duties of the street commissioner and city sexton, and such other officers not specially named in<pb n="276" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>this charter as the city council may from time to time see proper to appoint for the better administration of the affairs of the city, shall be prescribed by ordinances passed by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That bonds shall be required of the city assessor and collector, and of the city secretary and treasurer, in an amount not less than double the amount of the funds which may probably be in their hands at any one time, to be deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined by the council, which bonds shall be upon such condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as may be determined by the city council, and with good securities, to be approved by the city council; and the city shall in like manner require bonds of any officer or agent of the city through whose hands the moneys of the city may pass.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That the by-laws and ordinances of the city shall be enforced by fine not exceeding one hundred dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding thirty days; and the council may provide by ordinances that fines may be commuted by labor in a workhouse, or in the public works, and an execution may issue against the goods and chattels, lands and tenements of the offender.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That the salaries and fees of officers of said city shall be at the following rates, for each and every year, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencing from the date of their qualification, viz: The mayor shall receive three thousand dollars; each alderman shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive five dollars for every meeting of the city council at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tended by him; the recorder shall receive two thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; the secretary and treasurer shall receive twenty-five hundred dollars; the city marshal shall receive two thousand dollars and such fees as may be allowed by the city council; the assessor and collector shall receive such commissions as may be allowed by the city council, not to exceed the sum of five thousand dollars; the city attorney shall receive the sum of twenty-five hundred dollars; the street commissioner the sum of fifteen hundred dollars, and warrants shall be drawn monthly by the secretary for the payment of these salaries, but the city council shall have power to establish and fix the salaries and compensation of all officers and agents of the city, for the next succeeding year, commencing on day of general election, provided they shall not exceed the maximum above prescribed for the several officers named.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That the city council shall have power and authority to maintain the cleanliness of the city, to secure<pb n="277" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the safety and convenience of passing in the streets, side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks, and other public places in the city; to fix the squaring, and to prevent encroachments and obstructions on the streets and sidewalks, squares, ways, levees, and public roads and places; to determine the dimensions, and provide for grading, completing, maintaining and repairing of streets and pave<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments at the expense of the owners of the adjacent lands; to fix the place for anchoring of all water crafts on Buffalo bayou; to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of persons and premises; to prevent cattle, horses, swine, goats, geese, and animals from running at large in the streets; to establish and maintain a city police, prescribe the duties of policemen and regulate their conduct; to provide for lighting the streets, and for this purpose may establish gas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />works for the manufacture of gas for the use of the city and the inhabitants thereof at cost price; to determine in what part of the city slaughter-houses, bone-boilers, soap-boilers and other establishments for any business which is or may be injurious to the value of adjacent property, or unwholesome or disagreeable to the occupants of adjacent property, shall not be allowed to be erected; to determine in what part of the city wooden buildings shall not be erected, and within the limits prescribed no person shall be permitted to erect such buildings; to prevent gunpowder or other explosive material, kerosene oil or other inflammable oils being stored within the city limits in such quantities as to endanger the safety of ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jacent property; to provide means for the protection and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinguishment of conflagrations, and for the regulation, main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance and support of a fire department; to permit or [or] forbid theatres, balls and other public amusements, and to suppress the same whenever the preservation of order, tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quility or public safety may require; to close dram-shops, drinking saloons and other places where intoxicating liquors are sold whenever necessary or expedient; to define what shall be deemed nuisances in said city, and to abate them by sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mary proceedings; to provide a workhouse for vagabonds and disorderly persons who are unable to pay fines, and make regulations concerning the same; to provide and keep a city prison; to make all needful and proper rules and regulations concerning bakers, butchers, keepers of taverns, grog shops and other public houses, draymen, horse drivers, water carriers, omnibus drivers, hack drivers, and<pb n="278" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>drivers of baggage wagons, and especially to preserve order and prevent noise and confusion in and about the several depots on the arrival and departure of railway trains; to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent extortion by carriers of passengers and baggage, hacks, drays, and all public conveyances by establishing maximum rates of charges; to direct and control the laying and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of railroad tracks, turn-outs and switches, and to require that they be constructed and laid so as to interfere as little as possible with the ordinary travel and use of the streets; to require railroad companies to keep the streets through which they run in repair, and to light the same when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever deemed necessary; to construct and keep in repair bridges and crossing at the intersection of streets and ave<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nues, and over all ditches, sewers and culverts on the line of the railway; to regulate the speed of engines and locomotives within said city; to control and regulate everything concern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing street railways, and generally to make and establish all rules, regulations, by-laws, and ordinances, which may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribute to and promote the better administration of the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of said city, as well as for the maintenance of the peace, tranquillity and safety of said city and for the protection of persons and property of its inhabitants. The city council of the city of Houston are hereby empowered and authorized to take and condemn land and real estate in said city to the public use, viz: for streets, alleys and public ways; for ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending, straightening and widening those streets now in use; for public wharves and landing places for steamers and other water crafts, and for public squares, parks and pleasure grounds. For the condemnation of any land or real estate the following proceedings shall be had: The city attorney or attorneys employed by said city for that purpose, shall file a petition in the district court of Harris county against the owner of the land or real estate sought to be condemned for any of the purposes aforesaid, setting forth:</p>
<p>First. The name or names and residence of the owner or owners, if known, and if unknown the same shall be so stated.</p>
<p>Second. The description by metes and bounds of an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tual survey had for that purpose of the land or real estate sought to be condemned.</p>
<p>Third. The purpose for which the same is proposed to be taken and applied.</p>
<pb n="279" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Fourth. The supposed value of the property sought to be condemned.</p>
<p>Fifth. The prayer that the same be condemned to the public use, for the purpose as stated. And upon the filing of such petition, like proceedings shall be had thereon as in other civil suits, and when personal service cannot be had by reason of the defendant being a non-resident or unknown, service by publication shall be made as provided in other cases in the district court, and upon trial the court shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to render judgment condemning the land to public use upon the payment of the value thereof as assessed by the jury, and upon any suit being brought thereafter against the said corporation for such property so condemned, a copy of the judgment and an actual tender of the money in court shall be a sufficient answer in bar of a recovery in any such suit. All costs of proceeding for the condemnation of land and real estate under this act shall be taxed against the plaintiff, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluding reasonable fees of the attorney which the court shall appoint to represent the defendant when cited by publication.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That the city council shall have power and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to establish one or more markets and market places, and within reasonable hours, not later than ten o&#8217;clock daily, to prevent the sale of fresh meats, game, fresh fish, poultry, butter, eggs, vegetables, and such country produce as is usu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally sold in markets, at any place in said city other than in said markets so established; to rent and lease stalls and stands in said markets and market places, and collect market licen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ses and privileges, but no intoxicating liquors shall ever be sold in said markets or market places. To provide for the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spection of all things sold in said markets, and also for the inspection of the weights and measures used therein. To es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish public scales, and require all corn, grain, hay, oats, fodder and the like, brought to market in wagons and carts, and sold by the hundred weight, to be weighed thereon, and to charge a reasonable compensation therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That the market and market privileges of said city may be let and farmed out annually to the highest bidder, at public outcry at the market house, after ten days&#8217; notice of the time, place and terms shall have been published in two of the city papers, and two copies posted in conspicuous places in said market house. The city council shall, before the day of letting, fix upon the mini<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="280" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>mum sum at which the market and market privileges may be leased for the ensuing year, and publish the same in the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic notices required to be given as herein prescribed, and all bids below the amount named shall be rejected; at least five days before the day advertised for the letting, the mayor shall cause to be prepared the contract required to be signed by the lessee, and the same shall not in any manner be changed or modified within the five days previous to the letting; and said contract so prepared shall be open at the mayor&#8217;s office to the inspection of all parties who may desire to see it. A good bond and securities, to be approved by the city council, shall be required of the lessee, and new and additional securi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties may be required at any time, under penalty of forfeiture of contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That the city council may appropriate to such uses and purposes as may be deemed advisable, such halls and rooms in the upper stories of the new market house in said city as may not be necessary for public use, and to lease and rent the same from time to time for any term not exceeding one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That the city council shall have power to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct wharves on the banks of Buffalo bayou within the lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its of the corporation, and make such other improvements as may be necessary for the better navigation of said bayou, and for convenience of landing vessels and their cargoes, and to levy contributions upon all vessels and their cargoes as may land at the said wharves, and to demand and collect the same, to defray the expenses of such improvements and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pairs.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. That wherever any steamboat or other craft shall sink in the Buffalo bayou above Harrisburg, and the naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be obstructed thereby, it shall be the duty of the mayor of the city of Houston to appoint three good and discreet commissioners and inspect and examine the same, and its con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition, and immediately to report in writing their opinion, stating whether in their opinion the boat or craft sunk can be or is likely to be raised or removed within the space of ten days after their examination, and should they be of the opinion that such boat or craft is not likely to be raised so as to open the navigation within the space of twenty days from the time of their examination, then and in that case the mayor and alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men of the city of Houston may order the removal of such boat or craft so sunk, in any manner they shall deem<pb n="281" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>proper, without incurring any damages or penalty for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. That said corporation of the city of Houston is hereby given full power and authority to take such steps to preserve and improve the navigation of the said Buffalo bayou above the town of Harrisburg as they may think proper, and for that purpose they are authorized to levy and collect a tax on all steamboats and other crafts running in said bayou to the city of Houston, for the purpose of improving navigation thereof; provided, that the power in this section shall not be construed to give said corporation any jurisdiction or control over said Buffalo bayou or the banks thereof in any manner beyond or without the corporate limits of said city, except for the purpose of protecting or improving the navigation of said bayou, and shall not give said corporation jurisdiction or control to prevent or interfere with the construction of any railroad or other bridges, by any company or person, across said bayou in such manner as not to interfere with the navigation of said bayou.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. That the city council, by a vote of the majority of the whole number of aldermen taken by &#8220;yeas&#8221; and &#8220;nays&#8221; and entered upon their journal, shall have power to assess, license and tax hawkers, peddlers, auctioneers, theatrical and other exhibitions, shows and amusements, billiard tables, nine and ten pin alleys, public drays, wagons, omnibuses and carriages, grog shops, tippling houses and dram shops, beer saloons, (whether for the sale of domestic beers and liquors, or otherwise) and such other trades and occupations not es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pecially mentioned herein, as may be taxed by the laws of the State; but no assessment or license tax levied under this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall ever exceed three times the amount levied by the State on the same subject of taxation.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. That the city council, by a vote of a majority of the whole number of aldermen taken by &#8220;yeas&#8221; and &#8220;nays,&#8221; and entered upon their journal, may assess and collect an an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual and direct tax upon all property, real and personal, situ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate and being within the limits of the corporation, not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing two per cent. ad valorem all taxes on real estate, shall be a lien and charge upon the property, and it may be subjected to the payment of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. That every person or persons on whom, or on whose vocation a license tax may have been assessed, shall,<pb n="282" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>before engaging in such vocation, pay to the city assessor and collector the amount of said tax, taking his receipt there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for, which receipt shall entitle him, or her, or them, to a cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding license to be issued by the mayor. If any person or persons shall engage in any vocation within the limits of the city, on whom or which a license tax had been assessed by the city council, without having first obtained a license therefor from the mayor, such person or persons shall be lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble to pay one-fourth of the amount of each annual license tax for each week he, she or they may be so engaged, and in the same proportion for each day which may be recovered by action before the recorder or any justice of the peace, or the district court, according to the amount.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. That it shall be the duty of the assessor and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector, after the assessment of the property liable to taxation has been made, to call upon each tax payer for the amount of the taxes due by him, or them, and upon failure to pay the same, then the assessor and collector shall turn over to the city recorder the assessment rolls. The city recorder, upon receiving such assessment rolls, shall thereupon issue a sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mons to the party against whom any tax may have been as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed, to appear and show cause, if any said party have, why judgment should not be rendered against said party for the amount assessed against said party for taxes. Should the party not appear at the time and place, as summoned, judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be rendered against said party, as in a civil suit, and execution shall follow such judgment, and the costs shall be adjudged as in civil cases; and no property liable to taxa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be exempt from sale under such execution; and all laws governing justices&#8217; courts shall govern the city recorder in these cases. If the sum for taxes against any individual or corporation be greater in amount than that allowed by the jurisdiction of a justice of the peace, then the city assessor and collector shall file suit against him, her or them in the district court of Harris county, and the assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment books shall be taken as prima facie evidence of the state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments made therein and each assessment therein made by him, her or them, or his, her, or their agent shall be accepted as proved upon the trial before any court; provided, this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall not be construed to prevent the city council from adopting a mode and manner as near the mode and manner prescribed by the laws of the State, as the circumstances<pb n="283" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>will permit; and further provided, that all taxes due the city may be collected by an action of debt in any court having jurisdiction of the amount.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. That the said corporation shall not be liable to any person for damages or injuries caused from streets, ways, crossings, bridges or sidewalks being out of repair, unless the same were so out of repair from gross negligence of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration and remain so for ten days after special notice in writing given to the mayor or street commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. That it shall not be necessary in any action, suit or proceeding in which the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston shall be a party, that any bond or security shall be required, but all actions, suits or proceedings shall be conducted as if such bond, or security had been given. The property, real and personal, belonging to the city shall not be liable to be sold under any writ of execution, nor shall the funds in the hands of any person belonging to the city be liable to be garnisheed; nor shall the city or any of its officers or agents be required to answer to any writ of garnishment.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. That all cemetery lots which have been or may be hereafter laid out by said city, or in any private ceme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tery grounds, together with all monuments or railings upon the same, shall with all these appurtenances, forever be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from taxes, executions, attachments or forced sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. That no person shall be an incompetent judge, justice, witness or juror by reason of his being an inhabitant or freeholder in the city of Houston, in any action or pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding in which said city may be a party interested, and all officers of said city shall be exempt from jury service while holding their offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. That the property of all churches, Masons, or Odd Fellows, or other charitable associations, used by them for their places of meeting, both real and personal, shall be forever exempt from taxation. Bonds of the United States and bonds of the corporation of Houston shall not be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to tax under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. The city council shall annually appoint by ballot one person from each ward of the city, who, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the mayor as president thereof, shall constitute a board of health of the city. The city council may ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point a health physician and as many health inspectors as<pb n="284" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>they may deem necessary, and shall prescribe by ordinance the powers and duties of the board and its members; and the secretary of the city council shall be the clerk of the board of health, and shall keep a record of their proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings.</p>
<p>Sec. 41. The city council shall have power to take such measures as they may deem effectual to prevent the entrance of any pestilential, contagious or infectious diseases into the city: to stop, detain and examine for that purpose any person coming from any place infected or believed to be infected with such disease; to establish, maintain and regulate pest houses or hospitals within the city, or not exceeding five miles from its bounds; to cause any person who shall be suspected of being infected with any such disease to be sent to such pest house or hospitals; to remove from the city or destroy any furniture, wearing apparel, or property of any kind which shall be suspected of being tainted or infected with pestilence; to prevent persons from infected places coming into the city of Houston, and to adopt any sanitary measures whereby the health of the city may be protected or improved. But said corporation shall not have power or authority to prevent rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road trains and passengers therein from passing through said city, but may regulate the speed of such trains passing through and prevent their stopping.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. That all works of improvement and all public works for said city exceeding the sum of five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars ($500) in cost, shall be let out to the lowest bidder by sealed proposals, and no contract shall be made or entered into until after the plans and specifications shall have been prepared and submitted to the council and approved by it, and afterwards published in at least four issues of some daily paper published in the city, inviting bids therefor, and stating the time when such sealed proposals will be opened. No bid shall be considered unless made in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with the plans and specifications so published, and no allowance for extra work shall ever be made or paid for. The sealed proposals shall be addressed to the city sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary and treasurer, and shall only be opened in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence of the city council at a regular meeting, and the bid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ders shall have the right to be present. Bond and secu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rity, to be approved by the city council, shall be required of all contractors. The taking of any contract or any in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest therein, openly or secretly, directly or indirectly, by<pb n="285" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>any officer of the city, shall ipso facto work a forfeiture of the contract and the consideration thereof, and shall vacate the office held by the party taking the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 43. The city council shall have power and authority to borrow money on the credit of the city and issue bonds therefor, to an amount not to exceed one hundred thousand dollars during any one year; to create a debt during any one year exceeding one hundred thousand dollars, the question must be submitted to the registered voters of the city, and if two-thirds of the votes polled shall be in favor of creating such debt, it shall be lawful for the city council to authorize the issuance of the bonds for the amount named in the reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution or ordinance submitting the question to the voters. No bonds shall be issued drawing a greater rate of interest than ten per cent. per annum, but shall not be invalid if sold for less than their par value. All bonds shall express upon their face for what purpose they were issued. When any bonds are authorized to be issued, in the same ordinance, a fund shall be provided to pay the interest, and two per cent. per annum on the principal, as a sinking fund to redeem the bonds; and the two per cent. sinking fund shall be invested in the bonds of the city, or in United States bonds; the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation made for the interest and sinking fund shall, under no circumstances, be diverted to any other purpose. City scrip or other certificates of indebtedness or obligations of the city may be made receivable for taxes, but when paid in to the assessor and collector he shall require the party paying it in to cancel it by writing &#8220;cancelled&#8221; and the date and his name across the face of it; and at the same time the assessor and collector shall execute a receipt showing what amount was paid in money and what in scrip, and his monthly report shall correspond and give the names of the tax-payers.</p>
<p>Sec. 44. That a general election for mayor and alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men for said city shall be held on the first Tuesday in March, A. D. 1874, and the officers elected on that day shall, on the tenth day after said election, take the oath of office and enter upon the discharge of the duties of the office to which they have been elected, and until said officers shall be elected and qualified under this act, the following persons are hereby appointed the mayor and aldermen and recorder of said city, and shall immediately enter upon the discharge and duties of their offices:<pb n="286" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Mayor, James T. D. Wilson; aldermen for first ward, N. P. Turner, Whitfield Harral; for the second ward, Charles Gehr<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and F. Heitman; for third ward, W. C. Wagley and F. A. Rice; for the fourth ward, Wm. Christian and D. C. Smith; for the fifth ward, I. C. Lord and S. F. Noble; for recorder John H. Duncan. The officers so elected shall hold their offices until the first Monday in January, A. D. eighteen hundred and seventy-five, but the aldermen so elected shall determine by lot, immediately after the organization of the board, which of them shall hold for the long term as provided in section seven of this charter, and the term of such as hold for the long term shall expire on the first Monday in January, A. D. 1876.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. The Recorder of the City of Houston shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />officio the registrar of voters for the city; and the present recorder, viz., John H. Duncan, shall be the first Registrar, and in case of his death or refusal or inability to act, the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall appoint a proper person so to act. The registrar may appoint some suitable person in each ward to act as deputy registrar for such ward, and the registrar and deputies shall take an oath that they will faithfully and impartially discharge the duties of the office of registrar. The recorder may at his office register all voters in any ward of the city, and after the registration of the voters in the several wards has been completed, he shall transcribe the names of the voters so registered by him to the proper lists of the wards in which the voters reside. Books of registration shall be kept open in each ward for at least five days, of which notice shall be given by publication in one or more of the city papers of the time and place, and they shall be closed three days before the election, and after the books have been closed, no voter shall be registered. The registrar, and his deputies shall have authority to administer oaths to applicants for registration touching their qualifications as voters, and when not satisfied as to the right of the applicant to vote, or as to his identifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the registrar may require him to state under oath in what particular part of the city he resides, and also the names of at least two of his nearest neighbors, which shall be recorded op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posite his name for reference; and any person present shall have the right to require the registrar to put the question as to residence and neighborhood to any applicant. The names shall be numbered consecutively in the order of registration in each<pb n="287" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ward, and when the registration is completed, the names shall be arranged alphabetically on the lists for each ward, which shall be delivered to the manager of the election in each ward on the day of the election. Should the registrar or any deputy willfully and corruptly refuse to register any person entitled to vote, he shall be fined in the sum of five hundred dollars, upon indictment by the grand jury in the Criminal District Court of Harris county; and any person who shall unlawfully and wilfully vote at any election for officers of said city who is not a qualified voter under the charter, he shall be fined in the sum of five hundred dollars, or imprisoned in the county jail for the term of six months, or both, in the discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the jury, and the Criminal District Court of Harris county shall have jurisdiction thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. At the election to take place on the first Tuesday in March, 1874, the presiding justice of the peace of Harris county shall appoint a presiding officer and two judges of election in each ward, one of the judges from each of the political parties; he shall appoint the place in each ward for the holding of the election, and the election shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted as near as may be after the order of the State election law. The returns of election shall be made to the presiding justice of Harris county, who shall, on the fifth day after the election, proceed to count the votes and issue a certificate of election to the candidate receiving the highest number of votes for the respective offices, and the candidates so receiv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the certificates shall proceed to qualify and discharge the duties of the office, in accordance with this charter; and if the said presiding justice shall die, be unable, or refuse to act, then the city council herein appointed shall perform the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties assigned to said presiding justice. After said election the city council shall make such further regulations concerning registration and elections as may be necessary, and provide for the appointment of officers to conduct the elections in the fu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture. The registrar of voters shall be entitled, as compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for his services, to an amount not exceeding ten cents for each registered voter, to be paid by the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 47. That the general election for officers of said city shall be the first Monday in January of each year, commencing on the first Monday in January, A. D., 1875; and no election for officers for said city shall ever be held on the day of election for State and county officers. If it<pb n="288" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>should so happen that an election for State and county officers should be ordered on the first Monday in January, then and in that case the city election shall be postponed by the order of the mayor for one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 48. That an act entitled An Act to consolidate in one act and amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, in Harris county, passed August 2, 1870, and all former acts relative to the incorporation of the city of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton,&#8221; be and the same are hereby repealed; but all property, actions, rights of action, claims and demands, of every nature and kind whatever, vested in said corporation under and by virtue of the said laws hereby repealed, shall vest in and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main and inure to the said corporation under this act as fully and completely in all respects as if the said laws had not been repealed, and all by-laws, resolutions, and ordinances made and passed under or in pursuance of said laws, hereby repealed, shall continue and remain in full force and effect until re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed by the proper authorities of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 49. That this act shall be deemed a public act and judicial notice shall be taken thereof in all courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 50. That the provisions of the joint resolution of the Legislature entitled &#8220;a joint resolution, suspending the powers of the mayor and aldermen and other officers of the city of Houston, in Harris county, in certain cases enume<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated herein,&#8221; approved January 20, 1874, shall not apply to the mayor and aldermen and officers named, appointed, or elected under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 51. That this act shall take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 23, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to Incorporate the City of Galveston, and to grant a new Charter to said city, and to repeal all acts heretofore passed incorporating said city, which may be in force by virtue of any existing char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter, approved May 16, 1871.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two, of article three, of title two of said act, be amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="289" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion 2. At the first meeting of said board of aldermen so elected it shall proceed to divide as hereinafter provided, the three members from each ward into three classes; and those of the first class shall hold their office for one year; those of the second class for two years, and those of the third class for three years, and until their respective successors are duly elected and qualified, so that thereafter there shall be elected at each annual election four aldermen, who shall hold their offices for three years, and until their successors are elected and qualified. And at each annual election after the first, the aldermen shall be elected by general ticket for the city, and every qualified voter shall be allowed to cast but one bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lot each for the four candidates; the person having the highest number of votes in the whole city for mayor, shall be declared to be elected, and the persons receiving the highest number of votes cast for aldermen, shall be declared duly elected. In case the person elected mayor shall refuse to accept the office, the city council, mayor, or acting mayor, shall order another election; and in case of vacancy in the office of mayor by death, resignation, removal or otherwise, it shall be filled for the remainder of the term by a new election, to be ordered by the acting mayor or city council; and in case of a vacancy in the board of aldermen, by a refusal to accept or to qualify, or by death, resignation, removal or otherwise, the mayor or acting mayor or city council shall order a new election to fill the residue of the unexpired term; and all special elections shall be conducted in the same manner as is herein provided for the annual election; provided, that in special elections, five days notice thereof shall be deemed sufficient. When more than one alderman is to be elected at any election, the candi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />date receiving the highest number of votes shall be declared elected for the longest term. The candidate receiving the next highest number of votes shall be declared elected for the next longest term, and the candidate receiving the next highest number of votes shall be declared elected for the shortest term. In case of a tie they shall draw for classes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 24, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="290" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the County Court of Cameron county to issue Bonds for the purpose of funding the County Indebt<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edness, and to provide for the payment of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county court of Cameron county be, and is hereby authorized to issue bonds of said county, in denomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nations of fifty dollars and one hundred dollars, to an amount sufficient to cover the outstanding indebtedness of the county, which shall have accrued prior to the first day of January, A. D., 1874; said bonds to bear eight per cent, interest per annum, payable annually on the first day of January of each and every year, and shall run twenty years, payable at any time after two years; provided, that before such payment, the county court, through its presiding officer, shall advertise for proposals, and the bonds of the lowest bidder shall be paid; provided further, that none of such bonds shall be redeemed at a value above par.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The county court of said county shall, as soon as possible after the passage of this act, ascertain and audit the amount of outstanding indebtedness of the county, as shall have accrued before the first day of January, A. D. 1874, and shall thereafter issue the bonds of said county to a suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient amount to cover such indebtedness; and said county court is hereby authorized and required to levy and have collected a special ad valorem tax on all taxable property of said county, not to exceed one half of one per cent. for the purpose of paying the interest on said bonds, and to provide a sinking fund for the payment of the principal, in the amount and in the manner hereinbefore provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 24, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act incorporating &#8220;Waco Lodge No. 70 Independent Order of Odd Fellows.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That &#8220;Waco Lodge No. 70 Independent Order of<pb n="291" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Odd Fellows,&#8221; be and the same is hereby created a corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion under the name and style of Waco Lodge, No. 70, Inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendent Order of Odd Fellows, with a capacity in said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate name, to make contracts; to have a succession and a common seal; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; to make by-laws for the government and regulation of the same; and by said corporate name shall be capable of acquir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, holding, selling and conveying property, real, personal and mixed, and to do and perform any and all such acts as may be necessary or proper for, or incident to the fulfillment of its rights under the laws and in accordance with the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution of the State of Texas, and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the object for which this corporation is cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated, is for charitable and benevolent purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the place of business of this corporation shall be at Waco, McLennan county, Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this Corporation have perpetual succession.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this corporation shall have three trustees, a majority of whom shall constitue a quorum and be compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent to fill vacancies in the board, and to transact all business of the corporation; said trustees shall be elected annually, and at such time and place as the by-laws of the corporation may require, and said trustees shall choose one of their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber president, and shall appoint a secretary and treasurer, and such other officers as they may deem necessary for the corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration. The trustees may adopt by-laws for the government of the corporation; but such by-laws may be altered, changed or amended by a majority vote of the members of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion at any election or special meeting, ordered for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose by the trustees, on a written application of a majority of the members, and until the first general election of trustees as herein provided for. M. D. Herring, S. A. Killough and S. W. Mabry are hereby created and appointed trustees, with all powers, duties and rights imposed on trustees by the laws of this State and this charter, to hold and exercise the func<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of said appointment until the first general election of trustees as herein provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the corporation may convey lands by deed, sealed with the common seal of the corporation and signed by the president, or the presiding member or trustee of said corporation. Any such deed, when acknowledged by such officer to be the act of the corporation, or proved in the<pb n="292" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>manner prescribed for other conveyances of land, may be recorded in like manner and with the same effect as other deeds. This corporation shall have power to borrow money on the credit of the corporation, and may execute bonds or promissory notes therefor; and may pledge the property and income of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this charter be in force and take effect from and after the date of its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 26, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate the City of Brenham, and to grant a new Charter to said City,&#8221; approved February 4, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the city council, at least forty days before any general election to be held for city officers, to appoint a registrar, whose duty it shall be to regis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter the qualified voters of the city of Brenham, and who shall before entering upon the discharge of his duties, take the constitutional oath as provided for other officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That at least thirty-five days before any general annual election hereinafter to occur, the registrar shall give at least five days notice of the times and places he will attend in person in each ward, for the purpose of registering the voters of such ward; said notice shall be given by publication in a newspaper, if one be published in the city, and by posted notices in at least three public places in each ward. The books for registration shall be kept open at least three days in each ward; and after the registration in the wards shall have closed, the registrar shall register at the city hall, all person entitled to vote, up to within three days of the election.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the registrar to enter upon the registration list of each ward of the city the name of any person, resident in such ward, and entitled to vote therein; and for wilfully or corruptly refusing to register any person lawfully entitled to register, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="293" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fore any court of competent jurisdiction, be fined not less than one hundred ($100) dollars, nor more than five hundred ($500) dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. It shall be the duty of the city council to furnish the registrar with suitable books in which to register the voters of each ward separately; and the registrar shall three days before the election turn over to the city council said books with the names of the voters therein as registered.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The registrar shall be entitled to a fee of ten cents for each name registered or rejected by him, to be paid by the city, for which the city council shall make the necessary appropriation.</p>
<p>See. 6. That it shall be the duty of the board of aldermen to revise the lists of registered voters and to erase from said lists the name of any person that may appear from competent testi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mony to have been improperly registered or dead, or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise disqualified since his registration; and to add to said list the name of any person who may be entitled to vote, and shall furnish a satisfactory excuse for not registering before the registrar. For the purpose of revising the list of voters, the board shall sit at least two hours on each of the three days preceding the election, and on the last day when the duties of revision are over, they shall certify to the correctness of the list as delivered to them by the registrar, naming the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceptions or any changes that may have been made by them, and stating the last number of the list.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be the duty of the city clerk to furnish a certified copy of the list of voters in each ward to the judges of election of each ward on the morning of the election before the opening of the polls; and in no case shall the original list of registered voters be used.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. No person shall be entitled to vote unless his name appears upon the list of registered voters; and when a person has voted, the presiding officer having charge of the list, shall mark opposite the name of the person voting the letter &#8220;V,&#8221; and in no case shall the same list be used at any two elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That all registrations heretofore made of the voters of the city of Brenham, the same are hereby declared null and void and of no effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act shall take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 26, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="294" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to incorporate the City of Jeffer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, in Marion County, and to repeal all laws heretofore passed incorporating said city, or amendatory thereof,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 15, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section three of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Section 3. The municipal affairs of said city shall be administered by a mayor, and eight aldermen, who shall compose the city council; a clerk of the city, treasurer, chief of police, city attorney, recorder and policemen, the number thereof to be fixed by the city council, as well as their duties, salaries and fees; provided, the mayor shall be ex-officio recorder, and the clerk of the city shall be collector of taxes, and the treasurer shall be the assessor of taxes, and the chief of police shall be ex-officio street commissioner; and the clerk and treasurer shall be required to give bond for the faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful performance of the duties of their said offices, payable to the mayor of the city of Jefferson, in such sum as shall be provided by the mayor and aldermen and to be approved by them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section four of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 4. That the officers above named shall receive the following annual salaries, to be paid monthly in United States currency; mayor, eighteen hundred dollars; aldermen, two dollars for each meeting; city attorney, twelve hundred dollars; clerk of the city, twelve hundred dollars; treasurer, one thousand dollars; chief of police, twelve hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars, and such fees as may be allowed him by law, or by the city council; provided, however, that the provisions of this act shall not be operative until after the next, election of officers for said city.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the major, when acting as recorder, shall have all power conferred upon the recorder by section twenty of the act of which this is an amendment; and shall, when so acting, sign all official papers as mayor and ex-officio recorder of the city of Jefferson; and shall also have the right, when any person has been convicted of any offense and fined, and shall refuse to pay the fine, or shall be unable to pay the same, to require such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son to work upon the streets or other public works under the supervision of the chief of police, at the rates of<pb n="295" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one dollar per day until said fine and all costs shall be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charged.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the mayor and board of aldermen shall ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point, twenty days before an election for mayor and aldermen, a city registrar, who shall register all the persons who are entitled to vote at said election, and who shall be governed by the same laws that the registrar for the county is, and shall be entitled to the same fees, to be paid by the city, and who shall furnish a list of all persons entitled to vote to the officers who hold the election at every place of voting.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the twenty-seventh day of Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, 1874, at eleven o&#8217;clock and eleven minutes A. M., and was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out his signature.&#8212;A. W. DeBerry, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the County Court of Tyler County to levy a Special Tax for certain purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county court of Tyler county shall have power, at a regular session thereof, to levy a special tax upon all property subject to taxation in said county, for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of repairing the courthouse and jail thereof, and also to pay the outstanding indebtedness of said county; provided, that the tax herein authorized to be levied, shall not exceed in any one year one-half the amount of the tax levied by the State on such property so subject to taxation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said special tax shall be apportioned and collected in the manner provided by law for the collection of the State tax; and when collected, said tax shall be paid<pb n="296" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>into the county treasury, and the collector of said tax shall have power to enforce the collection thereof in the same man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as is provided by law for the enforcement of the collection of the State tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>January 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the thirty-first day of January, 1874, at three o&#8217;clock and thirty minutes P. M., and was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture.&#8212;A. W. DeBerry, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections one, two, and three, of an Act enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled &#8220;An Act to amend an Act to authorize the transcript of the Records of Bowie County,&#8221; approved April 3, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections one, two, and three, of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to amend an act to authorize the transcript of the records of Bowie county,&#8221; be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 1. That the county or police court of Bowie county be, and it is hereby authorized to cause to be transcribed into well bound books from the original records, now properly belonging to the office of the clerk of the district court of said county, such portions of said records as in the opinion of the court may be needful and necessary, and affix to the same a suitable index.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 2. That the compensation allowed for making such transcript shall not exceed fifteen cents for each one hundred words, and shall be paid for out of the general county fund, upon the order of the police or county court.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the clerk of the district court shall append to each book his certificate, under seal, showing that the same contains true copies of the original records;<pb n="297" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and such books, so certified to, shall have the same force and effect as the original records."</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 11, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act repealing an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to Prohibit the Sale or giving away of Spirituous, Vinous, Malt, and other Intoxicating Liquors, within two miles of certain places therein named,&#8221; passed May 31, A. D. 1873, (page 717 Special Laws, Thirteenth Legislature), or so much thereof as applies to the town of Moscow, or the &#8220;Moscow Masonic High School.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act passed May 31, A. D. 1873, entitled &#8220;An Act prohibiting the selling or giving away of spirituous, vinous, malt, and other intoxicating liquors, within two miles of certain places therein named, in so far as it related to the town of Moscow, or the &#8220;Moscow Masonic High School&#8221; be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 13, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to pay Judgment in favor of E. M. Smith, against the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, E. M. Smith did, under and by virtue of an act entitled &#8220;An Act for quieting the title to real estate in the city of Austin,&#8221; approved the eighteenth day of December, 1857, which said act was amended by the thirty-third section of article three of the constitution of 1866, recover a judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment on the twenty-second day of June, A. D. 1872, in the district court of and for Travis county, against the treasurer of the State, for the sum of two thousand six hundred and ninety-eight dollars and sixty-two cents, and all costs of suit, which said costs amount to the sum of twenty-six dollars and eighty-five cents, and</p>
<pb n="298" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Whereas, the original appropriation made for the payment of this claim has now become dormant, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two thousand seven hundred and twenty-five dollars and forty-seven cents, ($2725 47,) be, and is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the comptroller of public accounts be, and is hereby required to draw his warrant upon the treasurer for said sum in favor of E. M. Smith, or his attorney, W. A. Blackburn.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 21, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Agricultural, Mechanical and Blood Stock Association of Texas,&#8221; approved October 20, eighteen hundred and sixty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />six.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the said Agricultural, Mechanical and Blood Stock Association of Texas be and is hereby authorized to borrow money and issue its bonds therefor to any amount not exceeding fifty thousand dollars, and, to secure the same, may mortgage the property of said company; but before any such mortgage is made and executed, it shall be authorized by a vote of a majority of the stockholders in said corporation, at a meeting called for that purpose, after ten days&#8217; notice shall have been published in some paper published in the city of Houston.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 20, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="299" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the repayment to James J. Gathings, of Hill County, Money illegally extorted from him by the State Police.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the.... day of January, A. D. 1871, the State police, under command of Adjutant General Davidson, by force of arms, extorted from James J. Gathings the sum of one thousand dollars in gold coin, worth at the time in United States currency eleven hundred and fifty dollars; and the further sum of one thousand seven hundred and sixty-five dollars in United States currency, amounting in the aggre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gate, in United States currency, to the sum of two thousand nine hundred and fifteen dollars ($2915); and,</p>
<p>Whereas, The above amount has been erroneously and wrongfully used by the State in the payment of the State po<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lice, and the State credited with the amount; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic Accounts to issue to the said James J. Gathings, twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eight treasury warrants for one hundred dollars each, and issue one for one hundred and fifteen dollars, which said warrants shall be paid as other warrants or requisitions on the State treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the warrants herein provided for shall be receivable in payment, of any demands in favor of the State, either in the hands of the original holder or in the hands of any person to whom the same may be endorsed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 7, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Section thirteen of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Galveston Bank and Trust Company,&#8221; approved April 26, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section thirteen of the above recited act, which reads as follows: &#8220;Sec. 13. That if the sum of<pb n="300" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>five hundred thousand dollars be not subscribed and actually paid in within three years after the passage of this act, then all the privileges hereby and herein granted shall be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feited,&#8221; be and the same is hereby so amended as to read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 13. That if the sum of five hundred thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars be not subscribed, and two hundred and fifty thousand dollars be not actually paid in, within three years from the passage of the above recited act, then all the privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leges hereby and herein granted shall be forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the First Section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Texas Banking and Insurance Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; approved the twenty-eighth day of June, A. D., eighteen hundred and seventy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an act to incorporate the Texas Banking and Insurance Company, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 1. That J. M. Brandon, E. S. Jemison, W. L. Moody, R. S. &#8220;Willis, M. Quin, Geo. Schneider, J. C. Wallis, C. L. Cleveland, W. A. Fort, W. B. Wall, J. D. Skinner, Leon Blum, J. H. Littlefield, E. Randall, Selim Rinker, T. E. Compton, and their present and future associates, successors and assigns, be and hereby are incorporated and created a body politic and corporate, by the name of the Texas Banking and Insurance Company, and by the same name and style they and their successors shall be capable of suing and being sued, and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining any action to final judgment and execution, and shall be in law capable of purchasing, holding, improving and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying any estate, real, personal, or mixed, for the use of said corporation. And the said corporation shall have the power to ordain, establish and put in execution such by-laws, ordinances and regulations as shall be necessary for the government thereof; but for the enactment, altering or amending of such by-laws, it shall require. an affirmative<pb n="301" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>vote of two-thirds of all stock issued, while for the transac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of ordinary business a majority of stock shall constitute a quorum. And it shall be lawful for the said corporation, after the expiration of the term for which it was incorporated, to use the corporate name and style and capacity for the purpose of suits for the final settlement and liquidation of the affairs and accounts of the corporation, and for sale and distribution of their estate, real, personal and mixed, but not for any other purpose, nor for a period exceeding three years after the expiration of the charter.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 17, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the powers of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to levy a Special Tax in the County of Angelina,&#8221; passed May 23, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the powers granted in section one, of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to levy a special tax in the county of An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gelina, authorizing the county court of Angelina county to levy a special tax for the purpose of erecting a courthouse and jail in the town of Homer, the county seat of said county,&#8221; be and the same are hereby suspended until the first Monday in January, A. D. 1876.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 17, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act relating to the Headright Claim of Louis Rosseau to three hundred and twenty acres of Land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the grant of three hundred and twenty acres of land to the heirs of Louis Rosseau, by an act of the Legislature of the State of Texas, dated February 8, 1854, and erroneously granted to said heirs, be and the same is hereby annulled and made void.</p>
<pb n="302" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to cancel the headright certificate issued under said act to the heirs of said Louis Rosseau, for three hundred and twenty acres of land as his headright, and thereupon issue to said Louis Rosseau his proper headright certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the petition of said Louis Rosseau, the land certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, issued to said heirs of Louis Rosseau, and the evidences and papers accompanying said petition be duly filed by the clerk of this House with the Commissioner of the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 17, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections five (5), eight (8), seventeen (17), and nineteen (19), of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate the Orange, Jasper, and Shelby Railroad Company, and to Aid in the Construction of their Road.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections five (5), eight (8), seventeen (17), and nineteen (19), of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Orange, Jasper, and Shelby Railroad Company, and to aid in the construction of their road,&#8221; be, and are hereby amended as follows: That section five (5) of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Section 5. The capital stock of this company shall be one million of dollars, to be increased to such an amount not to exceed three million of dollars, as may be requisite to carry out the objects of this company, divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share to entitle its holder, or owner, to one vote in all meetings or elections of the stockholders; and a majority of the stock shall govern, except in cases otherwise specially provided for. The said shares of stock shall be deemed personal property, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded by the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary in the books of the company, kept by him in his office or in such other or further manner as the by-laws of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="303" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>pany may provide.&#8221; That section eight (8) of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 8. The said company is hereby invested with the right of locating and constructing, owning, operating and maintaining a railway, commencing at Sabine Pass, (Sabine city,) in Jefferson county, running thence to the town of Jasper, in Jasper county, thence, through the counties of Jasper, San Augustine, Shelby and Panola, and terminating at Marshall, in Harrison county, or Jefferson, in Marion county; provided, the freight and pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senger depots of said road shall be within a half mile of the courthouses in the town of Jasper or other county towns, when the direct line of said road passes within four miles of the courthouses of such towns; provided further, that each and every of said towns respectively, shall donate to said road, (the company owning it), the right of way with the nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary switches and turnouts, together with the necessary grounds for depots, not to exceed ten (10) acres.&#8221; That sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion seventeen (17) of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 17. That the gauge of this railway shall be three (3) feet or four feet eight and one half inches, at the option of said company; (provided, that should a three feet gauge be adopted, then only twelve sections of land per mile shall be granted by the State to said company, instead of the sixteen sections per mile that said company will be entitled to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive in the event of a four feet eight, and one half inch gauge being adopted); its railings (rails) shall be of such weight, not less than twenty-four pounds per yard, as may be determined upon by said company; and said road shall be well and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stantially built and fully equipped for passenger travel, and for the transportation of freight; and said corporation shall be subject to all laws now in force or that may hereafter be enacted by the Legislature governing railroads and railroad, companies in this State, both as to rates of freight and pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage, and as to the conduct of their officers and employees.&#8221; That section nineteen (19) of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 19. That eighty-five miles of this railway shall be completed within five years from the first day of January, A. D. 1874, and twenty miles each succeeding year, or this company shall forfeit all benefits from any land grants, except upon completed road. Said company shall also have author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity to construct, own, and maintain, in connection with said railway, a line of telegraph along said route.</p>
<pb n="304" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 20, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Southwestern Railroad Company, and to grant Lands to aid in the Construction of its Road.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Mifflin Kennedy, Richard King, Robert Dal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zell, Francisco Yturria, Jeremiah Galvan, Edward Downey, Wm. Kelly, of Brownsville; A. S. Thurmond, R. A. Upton, of Rockport; W. T. Norton, of Austin; J. W. Goodwin, of Bryan; J. H. Doran, of........; Santos Benevides, of La<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />redo, Texas; Joseph Cooper, of New Orleans, Louisiana, and James Stillman, of New York, and their associates, be and they are hereby appointed commissioners to open books and receive subscriptions to the capital stock of a corporation hereby created, and to be styled &#8220;The Southwestern Railroad Company.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a majority of the commissioners shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a board for the transaction of business, and shall hold meetings from time to time until directors shall be be elected as hereinafter provided for, and such commissioners may be represented by proxy under power of attorney.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That at the time of subscribing to the stock of this company, five per centum of the amount subscribed shall be paid in.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the subscribers to the capital stock of this company are hereby created and established a body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate and politic under the name and style of &#8220;The Southwestern Railroad Company,&#8221; with capacity to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract; to sued and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; to have succession and a common seal; to grant and receive; to hold and alien such real estate as may be granted by the State and individuals to aid in the construction of the road; to make and enforce by-laws for its general govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and the management of its business; and to do and perform generally all such acts as may be necessary and proper for the fulfillment of its obligations&#8212;the carrying out successfully the objects of this incorporation and the<pb n="305" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>maintenance of its rights and franchises under this act, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The capital stock of this company shall be two hundred and fifty thousand dollars, to be increased by a vote of a majority of the stock to such an amount not to exceed five millions of dollars, as may be requisite to carry out the object of this company, divided into shares of one hundred dollars; each share to entitle its owner and holder to one vote in all meetings or elections of the stockholders, and a majority of the stock shall govern, except in cases otherwise specially provided. The said shares of stock shall be deemed personal property, transferable only on the books of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, in such manner and under such restrictions and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as shall be provided in the by-laws of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the commissioners herein named shall solicit subscriptions to the capital stock of said company; and when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever one hundred thousand dollars shall have been subscribed, and five per cent, thereof paid to them, they shall at once pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to the organization of this company by calling a meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the subscribers, giving thirty days&#8217; notice thereof, and holding such meeting in the city of Brownsville, Texas: said notice to be published in one or more newspapers of the said city of Brownsville, and on the organization of the company said commissioners shall pay over any and all moneys in their hands to the treasurer of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the organization of this company shall be effected by the election of a board of directors, of not less than seven (7), chosen by and from the stock subscribers, at the first meeting called for that purpose, in the manner and within the time indicated in this act; and the said directors shall hold office until the next regular election, which shall take place annually in the city of Brownsville, Texas, at the company&#8217;s principal office, which is hereby made the legal domicile of the company, on the first Tuesday of January of each year; and in the board of directors so elected the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and control of this corporation and all its affairs shall be vested.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. A majority of the directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and at their first meeting shall elect one of their number president, and one vice-president, and shall appoint a secretary and treasurer, and as required, from time to time, such other officers and employees as may<pb n="306" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be found necessary to carry on the business of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company, when duly organized, shall be, and is hereby invested with the right of locating, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing, owning, operating and maintaining a railway, commencing at the water&#8217;s edge, at or near the usual land<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing place for vessels at Brazos de Santiago, on the Laguna Madre, Cameron county, Texas, and running on a direct line as near as practicable, view being had to the general and special topography of the country, via White&#8217;s ranch, on the Rio Grande river, or as near as convenient thereto, to the bank of the said Rio Grande river, within the corporate limits of the city of Brownsville, at or near Levee street of said city, thence to the city of Laredo, Webb county, Texas, and to the bank of the Rio Grande at said city, or to such point as the International railroad may touch the said river, together with such turnouts, branches and sidings and extensions as the company may deem it their interest to construct, with au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to construct, own, equip, and maintain, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after use one or more branch roads from such points on the main line of their road to such point or points on the bank of the Rio Grande river, between the city of Brownsville and the mouth of the said river, and between the cities of Browns<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville and Laredo, as the interest of the company may require; and said company shall have the right to purchase, construct and own any warehouses, docks, and wharves that may be convenient or necessary for the storage or transfer of freight transmitted to or from said road, and may charge therefor the rates usual for such accommodations; and said company is further authorized to construct, own, operate and maintain in connection with their said road, a telegraph line along their said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Any agreement in writing to subscribe for stock may be enforced according to the terms of subscription, and unless paid according to such terms, the directors may, after thirty days&#8217; notice, sell said delinquent stock, and transfer the shares of such delinquent to the purchaser; before said sale shall be made, the company shall notify, in writing, the subscriber of the time and place of sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company shall have power to borrow money, to issue bonds or other bills of credit, with or without mortgage, upon its railway, its capital stock, its<pb n="307" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>corporate franchises, and any and all its real or personal property, or any part or portion thereof, and to purchase property upon its own credit for the purpose of constructing and maintaining its railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That said company shall be subject to such gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral laws as are now, or that may be hereafter enacted for the regulation of railroad companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That said company shall not consolidate, lease or sell its road to any parallel or competing road, and any violation of the provisions of this section shall operate to forfeit the charter of said company; provided, said company may arrange with any other company to run over or use its road for the rolling stock of this company, and may run over or use such other road under such restrictions and regulations as are now, or may hereafter he prescribed by any general law of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. It shall be lawful for said company to enter upon, purchase, otherwise receive, take, hold, or obtain any lands for the purpose of locating, constructing, and maintaining said railway, with all the necessary depots, turnouts, sidings, extensions and buildings connected with said railway. When land cannot be obtained by agreement with the owner or owners thereof, the company shall pay such compensation as shall be determined in the manner hereinafter set forth; provided, that the land taken for this railway shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed two hundred feet in width, unless for depots and buildings.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Any person or persons whose land has been taken as aforesaid, without agreement or satisfactory com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation, may apply to the district court of the county for the appointment of appraisers, and said court shall thereupon appoint three, disinterested freeholders of said county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plicant and said company, to whom reasonable notice shall be given by the said freeholders; and said freeholders shall, after being duly sworn, and after due hearing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation to which the applicant may be entitled; that in determining the amount of damage, the enhanced value of the land, in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequence of the road, shall not be taken into consideration, and make return of their award at the next succeeding term of said court, and said award, if not rejected by said court for sufficient cause there shown, shall be entered up as the judgment of said court. During the inquiry as to<pb n="308" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the value of the land so taken, or the damage done to the estate of the owner, said company shall in no manner be molested or hindered in the prosecution of their work thereon or occupation of the same, but all officers of the law are authorized and required to render prompt assistance to said company in the premises.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That said railway company shall have the right to cross all public highways; to bridge all water courses; to construct, operate and maintain a ferry or ferries when nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary to further the interests and deliver the freight of said company, and to cross the track of any other railway that is necessary to intersect in establishing this railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the organization of this company shall be perfected within six months from the date of the passage of this act, and ten (10) miles of said road shall be completed within two years, and ten (10) miles each year thereafter, or this charter shall be forfeited as to that portion not built.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That this company shall have the right and the power to charge and collect such rates of freight and passage as the company may deem just and proper; provided, however, such charges are equal and uniform, and do not exceed the rates as are now or may hereafter be established by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That said company shall be entitled to receive from the State of Texas a grant of sixteen sections of land for every mile of its road hereafter constructed under the provisions of this act and put in good running order in this State; and said company shall alienate the lands hereby granted and donated, except so far as may be necessary for the ordinary uses and operating said road, as follows, viz: one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, and one-fourth in sixteen years, and the remaining one-fourth in twenty years from the date of the location of the certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates, in such manner that the whole of such lands shall pass out of the lands of said company within twenty years after the date of their location; provided, that said lands shall not be alienated to any other railroad company or corporation, except so far as may be necessary for the proper use and conducting of the business of such com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany or corporation; nor shall said lands be alienated to any individual, firm or company in trust for said railroad company, or to any firm or company of which any officer<pb n="309" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or stockholder of said railroad company is a member. And a failure to comply with the provisions of this act, and the general laws of the State on the subject, or a violation of the provisions of this act, and such general laws, shall work a for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feiture of all the benefits of this act; provided, that if said company shall construct the road herein provided for of a less gauge than four feet eight and a half inches in width, it shall be entitled to only twelve sections of land per mile of its road constructed and put in good running order; provided further, that the State of Texas shall not be liable for any deficiency in lands; provided further, that the gauge of said road shall not be less than three feet.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That whenever said company shall have com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted and put in good running order, as provided in this act, ten miles or more of its road, they may give notice thereof to the Governor of the State, whose duty it shall be to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point some skillful engineer (if there be no State engineer) to examine said completed road; and if upon the report of said engineer, under oath, it shall appear that said road has been constructed and equipped in a good and substantial manner, and in accordance with the provisions of the charter of the company, this act and the general laws in this State at the time regulating railroads, thereupon it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State to issue to said company certificates for six hundred and forty acres each, to the amount of sixteen sections per mile so completed and reported, if the gauge of said road is four feet eight and a half inches in width; but if of a less gauge he shall only issue certificates for six hundred and forty acres each, to the amount of twelve sections per mile; which said certificates shall be located and surveyed in alternate sections, the field notes and maps returned to the general land office and the odd sections patented to said company, and the even sections being reserved to the State for the school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That this charter shall remain in force for the period of ninety-nine years from the date of the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 20, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="310" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the International and Great Northern Eailroad Company to issue Bonds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the International and Great Northern Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company shall have power to borrow money on its bonds or notes at such rates as the directors may deem expedient, and to secure the same by mortgage or other lien upon its road or other property, or upon both; and said company may convert any bonds which may have been issued by either the International Railroad Company, or by the Houston and Great Northern Railroad Company into the stock of said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ternational and Great Northern Railroad Company, at such rates as the directors may deem expedient, or into a new bond to be issued in the name of the said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all bonds issued or debts and liabilities in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curred by either the International Railroad Company, or the Houston and Great northern Railroad Company, shall be of the same binding force and effect upon said International and Great northern Railroad Company, as they were upon the respective companies; and all acts heretofore done in the name of either of said companies shall have the same binding force and effect upon the said International and Great North<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern Railroad Company that they had upon the respective companies; and all fights or liabilities existing between said companies or either of them and the State or third parties, shall inure to said International and Great northern Railroad Company, the same as they existed with the respective com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 24, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to encourage Irrigation in El Paso County, by grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Land in aid thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any town or association of citizens of El<pb n="311" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Paso county be and are hereby authorized and invested with the right and the power to construct a suitable ditch or ditches of sufficient capacity to irrigate the valley of the Rio Grande, river in the county of El Paso; such ditches to be of an average width of not less than nine feet, and an average depth of not less than four feet, and the water from such ditches to be free to all citizens and land owners who will furnish their proportion of labor toward keeping the ditches clean and in repair, after the same shall have been con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed in accordance with the provisions of this act, and to be used and drawn from the main ditch under such restric<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and regulations as may be prescribed by the several towns who may construct a ditch or ditches as herein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, and when the same shall be constructed by an asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation of individuals under such rules, restrictions and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as may be prescribed by the county court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the State of Texas does hereby donate and grant to any town or association of individuals of El Paso county, who shall construct an irrigating ditch in accordance with the provisions of this act, eight (8) sections of land for every mile of ditch so constructed; provided, that land shall not be granted for any ditch of a less length than five miles.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever any town or association of indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viduals, as herein provided, shall have constructed and put in good order such a ditch, as is required by this act, application may be made to the Governor of the State to have the same examined, whose duty it shall be to require the State engi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neer, if there be any, and if not, then to appoint some compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent person to examine the same, and to make a report there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon; and if the Governor shall be satisfied from said report that the work has been done in compliance with this act, he shall certify this fact to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who, if as much or more than five miles in length of ditch has been made and put in use, shall issue to the said town or association of persons, eight (8) sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each mile so constructed, and so on for each mile thereafter constructed. The said cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates shall be located in alternate sections, and under the same conditions as those issued to railroad companies are re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be by the general laws of the State; provided, that if the public domain should be exhausted or otherwise<pb n="312" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>disposed of before these, certificates are located, they shall not constitute any claim whatever against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 25, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Hearne, Belton and North-Western Railroad Company, and aid in Constructing the same by granting Lands thereto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That W. S. Rather, J. W. Embree, H. C. Denny, L. T. Methvin, W. A. Miller and Jno. C. Henry, be and they are hereby appointed commissioners to open books and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive subscriptions to a capital stock of a corporation to be styled &#8220;The Hearne, Belton and North-Western Railroad Company.&#8221; A majority of said commissioners shall consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute a quorum to do business, and shall meet at such place as may be designated, within three months after the approval of this act, or as soon after as a majority thereof may agree upon, and they may appoint one or more of their members, or such other agents as they may select, to open books at such places as they may direct, to receive subscriptions for the stock of said company; and said commissioners shall hold meetings from time to time as their business may require, until directors shall be elected as hereinafter provided for. In receiving subscriptions to the capital stock, they shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire five per centum thereof to be paid at the time of sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribing, and any stock upon which the said five per centum is not paid shall be void, and the subscriber shall not be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to vote at any meeting of stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The subscribers to said capital stock, whenever they shall have selected directors, are hereby created and established a body corporate and politic under the name and style of &#8220;The Hearne, Belton and North-Western Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company,&#8221; with power to do and perform all things necessary and proper to the maintenance of its rights un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der this act, and not inconsistent with the Constitution of the State of Texas; to have, hold and own real estate; sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded.</p>
<pb n="313" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed two million dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share to entitle the owner thereof to one vote, in person or by proxy. A majority of votes cast shall govern in all cases not, otherwise provided by law, and said stock shall be deemed personal estate, transferable only on the books of the company by person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The direction and control of the affairs of the said company shall be vested in a board of not less than five nor more than nine directors, as the by-laws may provide, and they shall be chosen by the stockholders at their annual meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, the first of which shall be holden within one year after the passage of this act, at such time and place as the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion herein named shall designate. Said directors shall select one of their own body to be president of said company; shall fill vacancies in their board, appoint a secretary and a treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, and such other officers as they may deem necessary, and require bond, and make all rules for holding meetings and for their government; a majority of the directors shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum to do business, and shall have the power of a full board. All conveyances or contracts in writing, signed by the president and countersigned by the secretary, and other officers duly authorized by the board of directors under the seal of the company, when the same is in execution of an order of the board, shall be binding and valid.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That so soon as one hundred thousand dollars of the capital stock of the said company is subscribed they shall cause the first election of directors to be held, first giving notice of the time and place of such election by publication in two or more newspapers in the counties through which the road shall run; and when said directors shall be organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized, the said commissioners shall pay into the treasurer all moneys received upon subscription, and shall deliver to the president all books and other property belonging to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The said Hearne, Belton and North-Western Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company shall be required to construct and put in run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning operation ten miles of its said road within two years after the granting of this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That said company, when it shall be organized, shall be and it is hereby invested with the right of locating, constructing, owning, operating, and maintaining a rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="314" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>road at or near the city of Hearne, and running thence by the most direct route practicable, [route] through the county of Milam to a point in the present corporate limits of the town of Belton, in the county of Bell; thence to the town of Lampasas, in Lampasas county; and thence in a north<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />westerly direction to a point on the line of the Texas and Pacific Railroad, with the privilege of connecting with any other road or roads at their united intermediate or objective points.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the said Hearne, Belton and Forth-Western Railroad Company shall be entitled to receive sixteen (16) sections of land for every mile of road completed, or such quantity of land or other aid as may be granted under any general law of the State that may thereafter be enacted; and the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected to issue to said company certificates for said lands on the completion of the first ten miles of said road for the amount of land as above provided for; said ten miles, and the like amount on the completion of each subsequent ten miles.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the said Hearne, Belton and North-Western Railroad Company shall be governed by the general railroad law in its charges for freight and passage; in its securing and locating the right of way, they shall be entitled to take, as provided, lands not exceeding two hundred feet wide by compensating the owners thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This company shall be subject to all of the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral laws now in force, or which may hereafter be in force, with regard to running over the road of one company by another, and may form a junction and connect with another road in such manner as may best and most certainly secure the construction of their railroad.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company shall power to borrow money and issue its bonds, with or without mortgage; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that the same be done in conformity to the laws of the State of Texas, and the by-laws of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That this charter shall remain in force for the period of one hundred years from the time of its completion.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The failure of the company to comply with the requirements of this charter, shall operate a forfeiture of all that part of the road not then completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this act take effect and be in force from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 25, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="315" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to limit the amount to be issued in Bonds of the State to the International Railroad Company, and to provide for the payment of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Litigation has arisen on the claims of the Inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />national Railroad. Company for bonds of the State to aid in the construction of their railroad under the act of August 5, A. D. 1870; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, It is of the uttermost importance that the lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bilities of the State should be determined and definitely fixed, and all uncertainty as to the rights of said company should be removed; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, The said railroad company, by its authorized agent, has signified its desire to have a fair and equitable ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />justment in a spirit of just and reasonable compromise of all questions between the said company and the State; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the obligation of the State to aid in the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of the International railroad, by the donation of bonds to said company, in accordance with the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the International Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company, and to provide for the aid of the State of Texas in constructing the same,&#8221; passed August 5, A. D. 1870, be and the same is hereby limited to that portion of said line of said railroad now constructed and to be hereafter constructed between the city of Jefferson, in Marion County, and the city of San Antonio, in Bexar county, in accordance with the terms, provisions and restrictions of the above named act; and that when the said bonds are issued and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livered to said railroad company on the aforesaid portion of said line of railroad, in accordance with the terms and condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the above named act, the State shall be and is hereby discharged from all other and further liabilities to grant aid in bonds of the State to said railroad company. And the acceptance by said company of said bonds on said portion of said line shall be a full, final and complete settlement of all claims and demands on the part of said company for bonds of the State, as provided under and by virtue of the above named act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said bonds to be issued and delivered to said company on said portion of said railroad shall be<pb n="316" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>signed, registered and delivered to said company in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with the terms, conditions, provisions and restrictions set forth in the above named act of incorporation, and they shall conform in all respects to the bonds described in said act, and shall bear interest from the date of the inspector&#8217;s approval of each section of said railroad respectively.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That to meet the payments of interest on said bonds, and provide a sinking fund for the payment of the principal, when the same shall become due, there is hereby levied on all the property in the State, which is or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be subject to taxation by the State, a sum sufficient to pay said interest and provide a sinking fund, as required in the constitution for the payment of said bonds, which sum the Comptroller of the State shall cause to be assessed and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected annually, in the same manner and under the laws pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viding for the collection of State taxes for general purposes; provided, that the tax herein provided for shall not be as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed and collected by the Comptroller until after the decis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ion of the court as hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That on the acceptance of the provisions of this act by the stockholders of the International Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, which shall be done within forty days after the passage of this act, by a vote of the majority of the shares of stock of said company, and a certificate of said acceptance, signed by the chairman of said stockholders&#8217; meeting and certified by the secretary of said company, attested by the seal thereof, being filed in the office of the Secretary of State, it shall be the duty of the Governor to deliver to the president of said railroad company the bonds of the State, as provided in said above named act, on such part of said road as may then be constructed in accordance with the provisions of said act, and thereafter to deliver the bonds as aforesaid to said company on the aforesaid portion of the road, as the same shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed, in accordance with the terms of the above named act; provided, that bonds as aforesaid shall not be issued for a greater distance than three hundred and seventy miles; provided, this act shall not be held, considered or construed in any sense as a recognition of the power of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature to tax the people of this State for the purpose in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicated, nor shall this act be held or considered as in any way interfering with the litigation now pending between<pb n="317" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said railway company and the late Comptroller of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said bonds shall not be delivered as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said to said company, unless the Supreme Court of the State, in the suit instituted by said company against the late Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller of Public Accounts of the State, which suit was tried by the district court for Travis county at the June term, A. D. 1873, shall determine, in a decision on the merits, that said company is entitled to have and receive the said bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all laws and parts of laws inconsistent with this act are hereby appealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 25, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize the County Court of Comanche County to issue Bonds in the name of said County, for the purpose of erecting Public Buildings, and to fund the present indebtedness of said County.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section four of the above recited act shall be amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;That the county court of said county is hereby authorized to levy and collect a special tax upon all the property in said county taxed by the State;&#8221; provided, not more than one-quarter of one per cent, ad valorem shall be levied in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 28, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Gonzales Tap Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas,. That T. M. Harwood, W. D. W. Peck,<pb n="318" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>James F, Miller, T. S. Walker, J. C. Dilworth, George W, Littlefield, Hugh. Lewis, F. F. Wood, Benj. Botts, Adam Fisher, A. T. Bass, E. Lewis, L. H. Planck, and those whom they may associate with them, their successors or assigns, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, under the name of the &#8220;Gonzales Tap Railway Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; by and under that name they and the stockholders in the same, their successors and assigns shall have succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion for one hundred years, and are hereby granted the right, power and authority to enter into contracts to borrow money, to issue bonds, to execute mortgages, to have a common seal, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, and to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish such by-laws and regulations as the board of directors may seem proper, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State of Texas and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the persons above named, or a majority of them, shall act as commissioners to receive subscriptions to the capital stock of said company, and shall select from their number seven, to act as the first board of directors, and who shall continue in office until their successors are duly elected and qualified in accordance with the by-laws of said company, to be by them, or a majority of them, adopted. The capital stock of said company shall be one million dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and each share shall be entitled to one vote in all elections for directors, and in all stockholders&#8217; meeting, either personally or by proxy, and said shares shall be deemed personal property, and shall be transferred in writing, recorded by the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary in the books of the company, or in such other or further manner as the by-laws of said company may provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said company shall have the right, and the authority is hereby given them, to construct, equip, operate and own a line of railroad, together with a telegraph line, from the city of Gonzales, thence in a northerly direction to some eligible point of intersection with the Galveston, Harrisburg and San Antonio railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said, company shall have the right to make any and all preliminary surveys; to enter upon and take possession of lands to the extent of two hundred feet in width, for the purpose of roadbed and construction, and such additional quantity of lands for purpose of depots, sidings, turnouts, machine shops, and other buildings as<pb n="319" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may be necessary by any agreement had with the owner, if the property of private owners; and if no agreement can be made, or the owner or owners be absent or unknown or minors, then the property shall be acquired in accordance with the general railroad law of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The said company shall commence and have com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted said road within five years from and after the approval of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said company shall be entitled to all and any rights, powers, privileges, aid, benefits and immunities con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred by the general laws now existing, or that may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be passed by the Legislature of the State of Texas in relation to railroad corporations.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the State of Texas hereby donates and grants to said company sixteen sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each mile of railroad said company may complete and put in good running order on said line as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inafter provided. Whenever said company shall complete said railroad, they may inform the governor of the fact, and it shall be his duty to appoint some skillful engineer to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine said road; whose duty it shall be to examine the same and report thereon under oath to the commissioner of the general land office, and if it shall appear from such report that said railroad has been completed and put in good run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning order in accordance with this charter and the laws of the State, the said commissioner shall issue to said company sixteen land certificates of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railroad so completed by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the land certificates issued to said company under the provisions of this act, shall be located and surveyed in alternate sections, upon the unappropriated public domain of the State; that is to say, for each certificate so issued, shall cause to be surveyed two sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each adjoining, and shall return to the general, land office the field notes and maps, whereupon the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the general land office shall number said sections, and shall issue to said company or their assignees, patents to, the odd sections, the even sections being reserved to the State for the school fund; provided, the State shall in no event be, responsible or liable for any deficiency in the public domain; and the certificates issued to said company under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, not located because the public domain has<pb n="320" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>been, exhausted, shall constitute no claim against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said railroad company shall alienate the lands acquired under the provisions of this act, as follows: one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, one-fourth in sixteen years, and the remaining fourth in twenty years from the date of the issuance of said certificates, except so far as is proper and necessary for the use and conducting the business of said company; provided, said company shall not alienate said lands to any other corporation, except so far as may be necessary and proper for the conducting the business of said company; nor to any person, firm, or corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration, in trust for said company, nor to any firm or corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or company of which any of the officers or stockhold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers of said company are members; and any violation of, or failure to comply with the provisions of this section by said company, shall work a forfeiture of the lands so conveyed, contrary to the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said railroad company shall be subject to the laws of this State now or hereafter to be in force, and the State of Texas reserves the right at any and all times to regulate the freights and charges upon said road, and to regulate at any and all times the conduct of said company as a common carrier.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 28, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Midland, Gulf and New Orleans Railway, and to aid in the Construction of the Same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James McKaye, J. C. Colton, J. N. Smith, W. A. Taylor, Nelson Beall, J. U. Orvis, D. T. Chamber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lain, J. W. Downs, H. R. Martin, C. C. Campbell, G. W. Gentry, and J. B. Robertson, and their associates and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors be and they are hereby constituted and created a body corporate and politic under the name and style of &#8220;The Texas Midland, Gulf and New Orleans Railway Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="321" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>pany,&#8221; and by said name shall have succession and a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon seal, with capacity to contract and be contracted with, and in said name to sue and be sued; to plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded; to grant and receive; to make and enforce by-laws, rules and regulations for its government, and generally to do and perform all acts and things necessary and proper for its interests and to maintain its rights under this charter, that are not unlawful.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The direction and control of said corporation and of its business, shall be vested in a board of nine directors, to be chosen by the stockholders of the company at the meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing at which a permanent organization shall be effected, or as soon thereafter as practicable, and annually thereafter as may be regulated by the by-laws of the company. Said di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors may be residents or non-residents, and the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders shall have the power at any annual meeting of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />creasing their number to eleven, if deemed advisable. The persons named in the first section of this act shall constitute the first board of directors, and shall hold their offices until their successors have been elected and qualified, and their first meeting shall be held at such time and place as they may deem proper, after a call published thirty days in two newspapers of the State of Texas, signed by a majority of said board, when they may organize for business, appoint time and place for opening subscription books, fix the number of shares and amount of each, and when two hundred thousand dollars of the stock shall be subscribed, and ten per centum thereof paid in, they may call a meeting of the stockholders for permanent organization, by thirty days&#8217; no<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice in three newspapers, published in the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. A majority of the stockholders shall constitute a quorum to do business. They shall elect a president and vice president, shall fill all vacancies that may occur in their board; appoint a secretary and treasurer, and such other officers and agents as they may deem proper, and may require bond and security for the prompt and honest discharge of their duties; make all proper by-laws, rules and regulations for holding their meetings and other purposes that they may deem necessary or proper, not inconsistent with the general laws or this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock of said company shall be five million dollars, which may be increased by a vote of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the stockholders, representing two-thirds of the<pb n="322" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>stock, to such amount not exceeding ten million dollars, as may be deemed requisite to carry out the objects of the company, to be divided into shares of such amount as the directors may determine, each share to entitle the owner thereof to one vote in all meetings and elections in which the stockholders are entitled to vote, and a majority of voters shall govern in all cases not otherwise provided by law. Such stock shall be transferable in such manner as may be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by the by-laws of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the said railway company shall have power to borrow money and issue its bonds with or without mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage; provided, that the same be done in conformity to the laws of the State, and the by-laws of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The said company shall be and is hereby invested with the right of locating., constructing, owning, operating and maintaining a railway and telegraph line, beginning at some point on the Houston and Texas Central Railway, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the towns of Hearne and Bremond, in the county of Robertson, as may be found by said company most practical; thence crossing the Brazos river in a northwest direction, passing up the waters of the Bosque and Leon rivers, through Lie town of Comanche, in Comanche county, and to intersect the Texas and Pacific Railroad, in the county of Shackleford or Jones. If the line of said road shall pass within five miles of the county seat of any county, said company shall establish and maintain within one-half mile of the public square of such county seat a freight and passenger depot. Said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall not have the right to consolidate with, lease to or lease any line of railway running parallel with the said line of road, and no clause in this act shall be construed as to allow consolidation with any parallel line of road; and said company are hereby authorized to continue their line of road from the intersection of the Texas and Pacific road in the same general direction to the limits of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The said company shall have the right of way over the State of Texas on their line, and it shall be lawful for said company to enter upon, purchase or otherwise to receive, take, hold or obtain, in the manner provided by the laws of this State, any lands necessary for the purpose of locating, constructing and maintaining said railway with all needed depots, turnouts, sidings, extensions, machine shops and buildings connected with said railway. And when lands cannot be obtained by agreement, the lands<pb n="323" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>taken shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, unless for depots, turnouts, sidings, machine shops and so forth; and said company shall have the usual right of railways to cross and connect with other roads and to consolidate with any other road; and whenever the line shall pass over the public domain, the right of way two hundred feet wide with all necessary land for depots, turntables, sidings and so forth, with all rock and timber and earth necessary in the construction and maintenance of that portion, is hereby granted to the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said company shall commence the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of their road at any point on said line which may be deemed most advisable, within one year after permanent or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization, and shall complete and put in order twenty-five miles of their road within one year thereafter, and twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five miles each succeeding year thereafter until completed, and said permanent organization shall be perfected within six months after the passage of this act; and upon failure to do so said company shall forfeit all benefits under this charter, except on so much of their road as may be completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The State of Texas hereby donates and grants to said company, out of any unlocated public lands of the State, sixteen sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railway completed and put in running order by them; and whenever any section of ten miles has been so completed, the said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany may give notice thereof in writing to the Governor of the State, whereupon it shall be his duty to order the State Engineer, if there be one, or other competent engineer, if there be not, to examine said section and report under oath, and if said section be found to be so completed and in running order, then the Governor shall immediately cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tify the same to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, whose duty it shall be immediately to issue to said company sixteen land certificates of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of road completed, also one for each and every ten miles of road completed. All the certificates so issued shall be located in alternate sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, that is to say: for every sixteen sections located by said company, for its own use, it shall also locate sixteen other sections for the State, and return the field notes and the maps of the whole thirty-two sections to the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, who shall number said<pb n="324" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sections so surveyed and issue patents to said company for the sections numbered in odd numbers, reserving the even numbers for the school fund; and said company shall alienate their lands acquired under the provisions of this act, except so much thereof as may be necessary for the use and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessful operations. of their road, as follows: one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, one-fourth in sixteen years and the remaining one-fourth in twenty years from the date of the issuance of the certificates, in such manner that the whole shall pass out of the hands of the company within twenty years from the dates of the certificates; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that said lands shall not be alienated to any other railway company or corporation, except so far as may be necessary for the conducting of the proper business of said corporation, nor shall said lands be conveyed to any person, firm or company in trust for said railway company; and provided further, that the State shall not be liable for any deficiency of the public domain, and no land certificate issued under this act, which shall not be located by reason of such deficiency, shall never constitute any claim against the State. And on failure to comply with the provisions of this section, or any violation of the same, the said company shall forfeit all right to lands secured by this act not alienated according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The said railway company shall be constructed of such width of gauge as the directors may establish, not less than four feet eight and one-half inches; and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have the power to charge such rates of freight and passage as may be just and proper; provided, such rates be not higher than those that may be established by any general law of the State on the subject; and the right is ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressly reserved to the Legislature to fix the rate of charges for freight and passage by general laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="325" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental and amendatory of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to Incorporate the Texas and Midland Gulf and New Orleans Railway, and to aid in the Construction of the same,&#8221; passed at the present session of the Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section six of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;Section 6. The said company shall be, and is hereby invested with the right of locating, constructing, owning, operating and maintaining a railway and telegraph line, beginning at some point on the Houston and Texas Central railway, between the towns of Hearne and Bremond, in the county of Robertson, as may be found by said company most practicable, thence crossing the Brazos river in a northwesterly direction, passing up the waters of the Brazos, through the corporation of the town of Waco, thence up the waters of the Bosque and Leon rivers to the town of Comanche, in Comanche county, and to intersect the Texas and Pacific railroad in the county of Shackleford or Jones. If the line of said road shall pass within five miles of the county seat of any county, said company shall es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish and maintain, within one-half mile of the public square of such county seat, a freight and passenger depot. Said company shall not have the right to consolidate with, lease to, or lease any line of railway running parallel with the said line of road; and no clause in this act shall be construed as to allow consolidation with any parallel line of road; and said company are hereby authorized to continue their line of road from the intersection of the Texas and Pacific road in the same general direction to the limits of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29,1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Validate the Election for a Corporation and Officers of the Corporation of the Town of Carthage.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the election held in the town of Carthage<pb n="326" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>on the eleventh day of March, 1874, for a corporation or no corporation of said town, and an election held in said town on the sixth day of April, 1874, for the election of the officers of said town, be, and the same are hereby declared valid, and said town of Carthage is hereby declared to be legally incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated under the acts of the legislature of Texas, passed on the twenty-eighth day of January, 1858, and an act supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental thereto passed on the twenty-sixth day of May, 1873.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the Unconditional Certificate of Three Hundred and Twenty (320) Acres of Land issued to Josiah Powers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the unconditional headright of certificate No. 8, class 2, for three hundred and twenty acres of land issued to Josiah Powers, by the board of land commissioners of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Witt county, and dated April 10, A. D. 1848, be, and the same is legalized and validated; and that the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby authorized and directed to issue a patent on the same to the said Josiah Powers.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the &#8220;Henderson and Overton Branch Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That R. W. Oliver, Wiley Harris, Jiles S. Bog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gess, jr., Wm. S. Moss, A. B. Collins, J. H. McLarty, A. D. Tinsley, Webster Flanagan, Taylor Brown, sr., A. J. Smith, N. Gr. Bagley, Thomas Lloyd, Ras Redwine, R. R. Holton, T. J. Trammell, sr., T. H. Coleman, James Hamelton, James Cliborne, J. E. Norvell, T. J. Lacy, A. R. Crow, Ruben Cook, Dr. A. C. Heal, Arthur Buckner,<pb n="327" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and such others as they may associate with them, are hereby created a body politic and corporate under the name of the &#8220;Henderson and Overton Branch Railroad Company,&#8221; and by such name they may sue and be sued; make contracts; have and hold real and personal property by grant, donation or purchase, or sell, transfer or alienate the same. Said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have succession for ninety-nine years, and a cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said persons named in the first section of this act, their associates or assigns, shall constitute the first board of directors. They shall have the right to elect a pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident, vice president, secretary, treasurer and attorney; the other officers and agents of the company shall be appointed in such manner as the said directors may ordain and establish. The said directors shall have power to make by-laws, rules and regulations for their government, so as carry out the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent of this act, and to appoint an executive committee and confer upon it such powers as they may see fit, not inconsis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent with the laws of the State or United States, to provide for the future election of officers, and to fix the place for the principal office of the company, and change the same at pleas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure; to provide for issuing of stock and transfer of the same; to provide for issuing of the bonds of the company; to mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage and hypothecate the road bed; voting stock and all other property of said company; to raise funds to build or equip said road.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said company shall have the right to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct, own and operate a first class road of whatever guage they may see proper, from Overton on the International rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road to Henderson, in Rusk county, Texas. That said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have the right to connect their road with the Inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />national railroad at Overton; provided, that if the guage of the road is under four feet eight inches and a half and not less than three feet, the company shall be entitled to only twelve sections of land to the mile of its road so completed and constructed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said company shall have the right of way along their entire route, not to exceed two hundred feet in width over all lands of the State, and the free use of rock, timber, gravel and earth thereof, and the terms of the general laws of this State to procure the release of the right of way from the owners of the land along the route, and shall have the Tight to construct and operate a telegraph line along their<pb n="328" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>entire route, and to build and construct bridges across all streams along their line.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this company shall receive sixteen sections of land for every mile of said road that shall be constructed and put in good running order.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the capital stock of said company shall be two hundred thousand dollars, with the privilege of increase to any sum not to exceed six hundred thousand dollars, di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided into shares of one hundred dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said company shall have the whole line completed in five years from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Alamo Rifles of the City of San Antonio.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That George S. Deals, Henry C. Thompson, James R. Marmion, Alex. G. Schnetz, John W. Littell, John Kine<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />han, Thomas Hughes, A. J. Lockwood, N. J. Petrich, A. Prescott, C. K. Crawford, H. Wagenfehr, Joseph Schnetz, John A. Perris, B. F. Kelly, Andreas Coy, G. Fresch, James H. McLeary, H. L. Berg, L. C. Navarro, Anton Adam, W. H. Huston and Harry MacCormack, and others who are or may hereafter become associated with them in said company, and their successors, be and are hereby constituted a body corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate and politic under the name and style of &#8220;Alamo Rifles,&#8221; and by that name said corporation shall have succession and be capable in law to sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded; to ordain a constitution and by-laws for their government, not to conflict with this charter or any law of this State; and they shall have a common seal with any design they may choose; and to purchase, hold and sell real estate and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal property in any amount not exceeding fifty thousand dollars; and the said company shall elect their own officers, trustees and directors, and that there shall never be a less number of men in said company than twenty-five, nor a greater number than one hundred.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The officers and members of this company shall be exempt from common militia drills and jury duty.</p>
<pb n="329" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. The said company shall have power to provide by their constitution and by-laws for courts of investigation and courts martial to try all violations of their constitution, by-laws, rules and regulations, by any of their own members, and to punish such violations by suspension, expulsion, or fine not to exceed one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The said company shall have power to. collect all fines legally imposed by virtue of this charter, by suit in the court of the justice of the peace of precinct number one of Bexar county, and the certificate of the commanding officer of the company, attested by the secretary and authenticated by the common seal of the company, shall be sufficient evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the legal imposition of such fine, and judgment shall be rendered thereon and execution issue as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The commissioned officers of this company shall be one captain, one first lieutenant, and two second lieuten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ants, to be commissioned by the Governor, subject when or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered on duty to be trained and governed by the militia of the State, and the rules and regulations governing the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Whenever said company shall be called into active service by the Governor, or other person having lawful authority to call out the State militia, they shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to receive such camp and garrison equipage as is usually allowed and furnished to the best military companies by the government of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. This company shall at all times he subject to the civil authorities of the State, and to the orders of the Gover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nor of the State, in case their services are required.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The commanding officer of the company shall, on the first day of January in each year, file in the office of the clerk of the district court a complete list of all the officers and members of the company at that date.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The non-commissioned officers of this company shall be one orderly sergeant, four duty sergeants and four corporals.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The commissioned officers of the company shall be elected annually on the sixth day of March, or as soon thereafter as practicable, and the returns of the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be made by the orderly sergeant, under the seal of the company, to the chief justice of Bexar county, directed to the Governor of the State, who shall commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion such officers as soon as he receives the returns of the election.</p>
<pb n="330" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. All property, whether real or personal, belong<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the company shall be vested in the commissioned officers of the same, to be held in trust for the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. This act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 29, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit the sale of Intoxicating or Spirituous Liquors within two miles of certain places.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be unlawful for any person or persons to dispose of any intoxicating or spirituous liquors by sale or otherwise within two miles of the following places, to-wit: the Masonic Institute at Melrose, in Nacogdoches county; Millican, in Brazos county; Baylor University, in Independ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence, Washington county; New Hope Church and school<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house, in Johnson county; Pleasant Grove Church, Lamar county; Mt. Zabor Church, Lamar county; Antioch Church, Lamar county; Maysfield Academy, Milam county; Hepziah Church and schoolhouse, in Coryell county; Iradell school, in Bosque county; White House Church and Academy, in Smith county; Peoria, in Hill county; Lost Prairie, in Limestone county; Mount Pleasant camp ground and Ladonia Male and Female Seminary, Fannin county; Douglassville College, Cass county; Weston school-house, in the town of Weston, Collin county; Lancaster Masonic Institute, at Lancaster, Dallas county; Powell Dale, Bosque county; Merrilltown, Travis county; Dresden school-house, Navarro county; Hooker&#8217;s school-house, Rains county; Bristol, Ellis county; Forest Grove Church, Lamar county; Garden Valley, Smith county; Liberty Church, in Milam county; Woodbury, Hill county; Evans&#8217; school-house, Williamson county; Turner&#8217;s Point Academy, Kaufman county; Fitzgerald school-house, Ander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son county; Howard and Tunshire, in Bell county; Blossom Prairie depot, Lamar county; Aurora, in Wise county; Moul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, in Lavaca county; Heffner&#8217;s Chappel, in Hunt county; and Mantua, in Collin county.</p>
<pb n="331" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person or persons violating the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act shall, upon conviction thereof in any court of competent jurisdiction, be fined in any sum not less than ten nor more than one hundred dollars for each and every offense.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of January, 1875.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 30, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Company, and to grant State aid thereto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. R. Morris, M. N. Brewster, Charles Stew<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />art and their associates, be and are hereby appointed com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners to open books and receive subscriptions to the capital stock of a corporation hereby created to be styled: &#8220;The Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the majority of the commissioners shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a board for the transaction of business, and shall hold meetings from time to time until directors shall be elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That at the time of subscribing to the stock of this company, five per centum of the amount subscribed shall be paid to the commissioners or the directors, and whenever one hundred thousand dollars are subscribed the company shall be fully organized for the transaction of business.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The subscribers to the capital stock of this com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany are hereby established a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Company,&#8221; with capacity to contract, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to have succession and a common seal, to grant and receive, to make by-laws, and generally to do and perform all things necessary and proper to maintain their rights under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The capital stock of this company shall be two hundred thousand dollars, to be increased to such amount,<pb n="332" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>if required, as may be requisite to carry out the objects of this company, divided into shares of one hundred dollars each; each share shall entitle its holder and owner to one vote at all elections, and a majority of stock shall govern; the said shares of stock shall be deemed personal estate, trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferable only on the books of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The direction and control of said corporation and its affairs shall be vested in a board of seven directors to be chosen by the stockholders at an annual meeting, the first of which shall be held in the city of Houston, whenever one hundred thousand dollars shall have been subscribed and paid as heretofore provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum to do business; at their first meeting, they shall elect one of their body, president, and one vice-president. The board shall appoint a secretary and treasurer, and other officers requisite to carry on the business of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said company, when duly organized, shall be and is hereby invested with the right of locating, excavat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, constructing, owning, operating and maintaining a canal, commencing at or near Buffalo bayou, in or near the city of Houston, and running westerly either in the channel of Buf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />falo bayou or otherwise as the said company may elect, and terminating on the Brazos river in Austin or Waller county, with the privilege of erecting such dams, locks, tramways; water-wears and creating such slackwater navigation as may be deemed to the interest of the company and the successful maintenance and operation of said canal.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. It shall be lawful for said company to enter upon, purchase, or otherwise receive, take, hold and appropriate any lands necessary for locating, constructing, excavating or em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />banking and maintaining said canal, with all the necessary locks, water-wear approaches, inlets or outlets connected with or useful to the operators of said canal; when land cannot be obtained by agreement, the land taken for this canal shall not exceed one hundred and fifty yards in width, unless for buildings, waste water-locks, or other necessary conveniences during the construction and operation of said canal.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said company shall have the right to cross all public highways, and all railroads that it may be necessary to cross to establish and complete said canal, erecting such bridges and crossings as the various cases<pb n="333" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may require; provided, that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to confer any right upon said company to preju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dice the navigation of the Brazos river.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the said canal company shall have the power to borrow money, issue bonds or bills of credit, with or without mortgage; provided, it is done in conformity to a vote of two-thirds of the directors; and generally this com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have all the power requisite to carry into effect the objects of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That this canal shall be constructed not less than thirty feet wide at its surface, and of not less depth than three feet, with locks, when requisite, of sufficient ca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pacity to pass boats, lumber rafts, or other craft at least twenty feet in width, and sixty feet in length; and that all boats, barges, rafts or craft, navigating or passing through this canal, shall be entitled to right of passage and locking in their due order of arrival.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That said company are authorized to construct, own, and navigate any and all craft, boat and barges required for transportation, either on the bodies of said canal, slack<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />waters, created or existing, connected with the waters of the canal, or any navigable waters with which said canal may connect by lockage or otherwise; that the company shall be able to contract for and charge and collect pay for the use of water drawn from their canal for hydraulic power or for irrigation, at such rates and prices as may be agreed upon by the persons wishing the use thereof, but in no case shall the said company flow lands to the detriment of owners without their consent, or on due payment to the parties aggrieved.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this company shall have power to charge and collect such rates of freight, and such water rates as they may deem just and proper; provided, that freight rates shall not exceed, by the pound, avoirdupois, or by the cubic foot, over the rates allowed by law on railroad freights over the same distances.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The first meeting of the company shall be called by the commissioners whenever one hundred thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars of the capital stock shall have been subscribed, by giving thirty days&#8217; notice in some paper published in Houston, and the stockholders shall then proceed to elect directors, who shall hold office until the annual election, which shall take place in the city of Houston, on the first Tuesday of January, in each year; should a majority of<pb n="334" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the stock be represented, the election shall proceed; if not, directors shall appoint another, within thirty days there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, and an election on that day shall be valid; directors elected under the provisions hereof, shall hold their office for one year, and until their successors are duly elected and qualified. No person shall be a director who does not own at least ten shares of the capital stock of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the State of Texas hereby donates and grants to the said canal company for the purpose of aiding in its construction, out of any unlocated public lands of the State, eight sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of canal constructed and put in substantial canal navigating order by them, and whenever any section of ten miles of said canal has been completed, the said company, through its president or secretary, may give notice of the same to the Governor of this State, in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, whose duty it shall be on the receipt of said notice, to order the State engineer, if there be any, or if not, to appoint a skillful engineer to examine said section of said canal, and report under oath; and if said section of ten miles of said canal be found to be constructed and in good boating order in a substantial manner, then the Governor shall certify the same to the commissioner of the general land office, and he shall issue to said canal company eight land certificates of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of canal so constructed and put in navigating order, and in like manner with each and every succeeding section of ten miles of said canal, until the whole has been completed; all the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates issued as above to said company shall be located by them in alternate sections; that is to say: for every eight sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions located by said company for its own use, said company shall locate also for the State at the same time, other eight sections of land for the State, and return the field notes and maps of the whole sixteen sections to the commissioner of the general land office, who shall number said sections so surveyed, and issue patents to said company for the sections numbered in odd numbers, reserving the even numbers for the school fund, and said company shall alienate their said lands acquired under the provisions of this act, except so much thereof as may be necessary for the uses and successful operation of their canal, as follows: one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="335" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fourth in sixteen years, and the remaining one-fourth in twenty years from the date and issuance of the said certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates; provided, said company shall not alienate or sell said lands to any other corporation, nor to any person or firm in trust for said company, nor to any firm or corporation of which any officer or stockholder is a member. And on failure to comply with the provisions of this section, or on violation of the same, said company shall forfeit all benefits under this charter; provided further, that the State shall in no case be liable for a deficiency of public domain, and no land certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate issued under the provisions of this act, which may not be located because of the previous exhaustion of the public domain, shall ever constitute any claim against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the charter shall remain in force and effect for the period of fifty years from the date of the completion of said canal, and said company shall be entitled to, and shall receive from the State such loans or assistance, advantages, or immunities as may be granted to any canal company, or to. which any companies engaged in internal improvements shall be entitled to receive or shall obtain from the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 1, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate the Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, and to grant State aid thereto,&#8221; passed at the First Session of the Fourteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the before named Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Company shall finish, and complete at least five miles of the work proposed in said act within five years from the passage thereof, and shall finish and complete the whole work within fifteen years therefrom, otherwise its rights granted in said act shall be forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 1, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="336" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the South-Western and Rio Grande Railroad Company and aid in the construction of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That L. T. Barrett, B. Hardeman, H. J. Mathews, W. H. Swift, William Martin, J. D. Martin, J. C. Swift, Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam Carrow, Wm. P. Wilson, E. S. Hicks, R. L. Parker and Fred. Voigt, of the State of Texas, and James Heffner, Charles W. Kutting, Thomas Poland, Wm. E. Hamilton, N. W. Murphy, W. S. Haren, Benj. Jacobs, and James B. Foster, of the State of Louisiana, and all such persons as shall or may be associated with them, and their successors, are hereby cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mated a body politic and corporate in fact and in law, by the name of the &#8220;South-Western and Rio Grande Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; and by that name shall have perpetual succession, and shall be able to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fend and be defended in all courts of law and equity, and make and have a common seal, and the same to alter at the pleasure of the board of directors.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company and corporation is authorized to lay out, construct, finish and maintain, operate and enjoy a continuous railroad and telegraph line, with all appurte<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances, namely: beginning on the western bank of the Sabine river, opposite or in the vicinity of Logansport, State of Loui<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siana, thence in a south-westerly direction by the way of Cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter, in Shelby county, and Nacogdoches, in Nacogdoches county, to Belton, in Bell county, or within one half mile of those places, if the road runs within five miles of said places; thence to the town of Burnett, in Burnett county, by the most practicable route to be determined by the board of directors, to or in the vicinity of the mouth of the Rio Pecos river, on the Bio Grande river; provided, that whenever the direct line of said road shall run within five miles of any county seat, the company shall establish and continue a passenger and freight depot, in one half mile of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, that the amount of stock to be subscribed, necessary to an organization, shall not be less than one hundred thousand dollars, in shares of one hundred dollars each, of which amount of stock ten per<pb n="337" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>cent, shall have been paid in; that the capital stock of said corporation shall not be less than five hundred thousand dollars, and shall not exceed five millions of dollars, unless by a majority of the stockholders, each share of stock being entitled to one vote, which capital stock shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each; and the payment on said shares of stock shall be made in such manner and upon such notice as may be made and provided by the board of directors; provided, that payments on said shares of stock shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed twenty-five per cent, thereof at any one time, nor be made oftener than once every sixty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, that the first meeting of the above named incorporators shall be held at the domicile, in this State, of said company, within six months from the passage of this act, which domicile shall be definitely lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated by the above named incorporators at their first meeting; and on designating the domicile of said company as aforesaid, the said company shall immediately report the same to the General Land Office of this State, under the seal of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany. A notice of said meeting shall be published for four successive weeks, in a newspaper published along the proposed line of said railroad. And ten miles of said railroad shall be completed and put in good running order within two years from and after the passage of this act, and twenty miles every year thereafter until completed, or this charter shall be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feited as to the part not built.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That at the first meeting of the said incorporators they shall elect a president, vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />president and secretary, and immediately open books for the subscription, of the stock necessary for organization; upon taking which stock, ten per cent, of which shall be paid in, they shall elect a president, vice-president and thirteen direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors; each share of stock, as aforesaid, being entitled to one vote; on which complete organization they shall as soon as practicable open books for subscription to the capital stock of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all suits for said company shall be prosecuted in the name of the president of said corporation, and all notices and legal process shall be served on said officer, or in case of his death, absence, or resignation, upon the vice-president of said company. Annual meetings of the stockholders in said corporation,<pb n="338" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for the choice of officers and the transaction of the business of the company, shall be held at the domicile of the company, at such time and upon such notice as may be prescribed by the by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the said South-Western and Bio Grande Railroad Company shall have the power to make such by-laws and regulations as may be deemed best for the proper management and government of said company, the same not to be inconsistent with the objects of this charter or the laws of the State. Each stockholder in the enactment of said by-laws shall be entitled to one vote for each share of stock held by him, and may vote in person or by written proxy. It shall further require a vote of the majority of the said stockholders to establish such by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the right of way is hereby granted to the said South-Western and Rio Grande Railroad Company and its successors for the construction of a railroad and telegraph, as proposed, and the right of way is granted to said company to the extent of one hundred feet in width on each side of said railroad, including all necessary grounds for workshops, switches, sidings, turn-tables, depots and water-tanks. That the said South-Western and Rio Grande Railroad Company is hereby authorized to enter upon, take and hold any lands or premises that may be necessary for the construction and working of said road not exceeding one hundred feet on each side of said road; and the said company shall have the right to cut and remove trees, drift and other material that might, by falling or drifting, encumber its road bed, although being or standing more than one hundred and fifty feet from the line of said road; and in case the owner of said land or premises and the said company cannot agree as to the value of said lands or premises so taken, or to be taken, for the use of said company, the value thereof shall be determined by the appraisal of three disinterested com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, who may be appointed upon application of either party by the district, court of the county where the land lies; and said commissioners, in their assessment of damages, shall appraise such lands or premises at what would have been the value if the road had not been built; and upon return into court of such appraisement, and pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment into the same of the estimated value for the benefit of the owner, said premises shall be deemed taken by said<pb n="339" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>company, which shall acquire full title to the same for the purposes aforesaid; and either party being aggrieved at such appraisement may, within thirty days after the same has been returned into said court, file an appeal therefrom and demand a jury of twelve men to estimate the damages sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained. Said appraisal shall not interfere with the rights of said company to enter upon said lands or premises or prevent the said company from continuing the construction of said road. The said party appealing shall give bonds, with suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient surety or sureties, to be approved by the judge of said court, for any costs or damages that may arise on said appeal. And in case any of the lands or premises taken, or to be taken, as aforesaid, shall be held by any infant heirs or insane per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, residing without the State of Texas, and not represented by any administrator or guardian, the said judge of said court may appoint a guardian or attorney ad hoc to appear in proper person in their behalf, who shall give bond for the faithful execution of his trust, who may represent in court the person or persons disqualified as aforesaid, when action in reference to the appraisement of the premises or lands taken, or to be taken, for the use of said company shall be had with the same effect as has already been described as to the final vestment of title as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, that the said South-West<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern and Rio Grande Railroad Company may issue their first mortgage bonds, to an amount not exceeding forty thousand dollars per mile, haying not less than twenty years to run, which bonds shall be a first lien upon said road, and the property and equipments of the same; and shall bear not more than eight per cent, interest per annum, payable semi-an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually, in gold, at such times and places as said company may determine; such bonds and mortgages shall be filed and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded in the office of the recorder of mortgages and deeds in the county in which the domicile of the company is located.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this company shall have the right and the power to charge and collect such rates of freight and passage as the company may deem just and proper; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, however, such charges do not exceed the rates as are now or may hereafter be established by law; provided, that the amount to be charged by said company for the carriage of freight and passengers shall be subject to be<pb n="340" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>regulated from time to time by the Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company shall be entitled to receive from the State of Texas a grant of sixteen sections of land for every mile of its road hereafter constructed under the provisions of this act, and put in good running order in this State; provided, the gauge of the road is four feet eight and a half inches, and twelve sections of land for every mile constructed, should the gauge of the road he three feet; and said company shall alienate the lands hereby granted and donated, except so far as may be necessary for the ordinary uses and operating said road as follows, to wit: one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, one-fourth in six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen years, and the remaining one-fourth in twenty years, from the date of the location of the certificate, in such manner that the whole of such lands shall pass out of the hands of said company within twenty years after the date of their location; provided, that said lands shall not be alienated to any other railroad company or corporation, except so far as may be necessary for the proper use and conducting of the business of such company or corporation, nor shall said lands be alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated to any individual, firm or corporation in trust for said railroad company, or to any firm or company of which any officer or stockholder of said railroad company is a member; and a failure to comply with the provisions of this act and the general laws of the State on the subject, or a violation of the provisions of this act and such general laws, shall work a forfeiture of all the benefits of this act; provided, that the State of Texas shall not be liable for any deficiency in lands; provided further, that the gauge of said road shall not exceed four feet eight inches and a half, and not less than three feet in width.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That whenever said company shall have com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted and put in good running order, as provided in this act, ten miles or more of its road, they may give notice thereof to the Governor of the State, whose duty it shall be to appoint some skillful engineer (if there be no State engineer) to examine said completed road; and if upon the report of said engineer, under oath, it shall appear that said road has been constructed and equipped in a good and substantial manner, and in accordance with the provisions of the charter of the company, this act and the general laws in this State at the time regulating railroads, thereupon<pb n="341" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State to issue to said company certificates for six hundred and forty acres each, to the amount of sixteen sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions per mile so completed and reported, which said certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates shall be located and surveyed in alternate sections, the field notes and maps returned to the general land office, and the odd sections patented to said company, and the even sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions being reserved to the State for the school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That this charter shall remain in force for the period of ninety-nine years from the date of the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That said road, it the line of same shall touch the limits of the county of Leon, shall establish a depot in one half mile of the public square of the town of Centre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville, in said county of Leon.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 1, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to grant Lands to the International Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, in lieu of Bonds, on a portion of its line of road.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That so much of the International railroad as may be hereafter constructed west of the city of San Antonio, in the county of Bexar, to a point at or near the city of Laredo, in the county of Webb, on the Rio Grande river, in accordance with the provisions of its charter, passed August 5, A. D. 1870, the said company shall be entitled to have and receive from the State of Texas, twenty sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of said road con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed as aforesaid; provided, that the said company shall not be required to construct the road east of Jefferson, and the State shall be relieved from any obligation upon that part of the road; and provided further, that this act shall not be construed as an admission on the part of this Legislature, that said company are entitled to any subsidy from the State of Texas by reason of any act of a former Legislature.</p>
<pb n="342" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That on application of the president of said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road company for the inspection of ten miles or more of said portion of said road, it shall be the duty of the Governor to cause such section to be inspected by the State engineer, or some competent person. The person so appointed to inspect the same shall make an examination thereof without, delay, and on his report, in writing, under oath, that the same has been substantially built, it shall be the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the Land Office to issue and deliver to the president of said company or any duly authorized agent thereof, twenty certificates, for six hundred and forty acres of land each, for each and every mile of said portion of said road so constructed, and in like manner for each additional section of ten miles or more as the same may be constructed; which said certificates may be located, surveyed, and patented on any of the unap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated public domain of the State, in accordance with the laws relating to the appropriation of the public lands to railroad companies; provided, the State shall be in no wise liable for, or on account of any deficiency in the vacant pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic domain.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 1, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Liberty Fire Company No. 2, of the City of Houston, to Raise, Provide for, and Administer a Charity Fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the said &#8220;Liberty Fire Company No. 2,&#8221; shall have power and authority to raise, provide for, hold and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minister a charity fund for the benefit of its members and other eleemosynary purposes; and to this end and purpose the said company may accept, receive, and take gifts, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quests and devises of money and other property for said char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity fund, or upon special trusts for objects and purposes of like character.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all moneys and other property which have heretofore been appropriated and set apart to the relief fund, and which may hereafter, from time to time be<pb n="343" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>appropriated and set apart to said fund, together with five per centum of the interest and profits accruing therefrom, shall constitute a perpetual fund, which shall not be diverted or appropriated to any other use or purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said charity fund shall be managed and controlled, invested and reinvested, by three members of said company, who shall constitute a board of trustees. The said board shall be elected at some regular meeting, to be held within ninety days after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When a vacancy occurs in the hoard of trustees it shall be immediately filled by the remaining members of the board appointing another member of the company, and should the board of trustees fail to fill the vacancy before two regular meetings of the company shall have been held, it may then be filled by the company at a regular meeting from among its members.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the legal title to all money, property, and effects belonging to said charity fund, shall be held in the name of the trustees for the use of said company, and may be disposed of by them, or any two of them. Said trustees shall keep a record and account, of all their transactions as trustees, and shall make semi-annually reports to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany at the regular monthly meetings, held in January and July. That the said trustees shall not, under any circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances, be entitled to any commissions, compensation or emol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uments, and in the administration and management of said fund, the said trustees shall exercise a sound discretion, and act as a reasonably prudent man would act in the management of his own business, and so acting they shall be liable for no loss that max happen.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the caption of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Rockport, Fulton, Laredo and Mexican Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cific Railroad Company,&#8221; approved March 11, 1871, and to change the name of said Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the caption of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to<pb n="344" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>incorporate the Rockport, Fulton, Laredo and Mexican Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cific Railroad Company,&#8221; approved March 11, 1871, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Texas and Mexican Pacific Railroad Company.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the name of said railroad company shall hereafter be &#8220;The Texas and Mexican Pacific Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; and that all bonds issued by said company, and all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings by and against said company, shall hereafter be in the name of said company as changed and specified by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Caddo, Paris and Jefferson Branch of the Missouri Kansas and Texas Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That W. M. Harrison, W. L. Crawford and J. H. Bemis, of the city of Jefferson; Geo. Chambers, of Titus county; F. M. Smith, of Red River county; J. W. Broad, W. B. Wright, and J. W. Hardison, of the city of Paris; J. B. Barrett and W. D. Merrick, of Sedalia, Missouri; and Francis Skiddy, of New York, their associates, successors and assigns, be and are hereby constituted and appointed a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the &#8220;Caddo, Paris and Jefferson Branch of the Missouri, Kansas and Texas Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way Company,&#8221; and as such shall have succession for sixty years, and a common seal; shall have power to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; receive grants, gifts and do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nations; buy, hold, sell and convey property, real, personal and mixed; make by-laws, rules and regulations for their gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral government, and generally to do all things and acts necessary to its interests and not unlawful.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The persons named in the first section of this act shall constitute the first board of directors, and shall hold their office for one year, or until their successors have been elected and qualified; a majority of them shall be a<pb n="345" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>quorum, and their first meeting shall be held at such time and place as they may deem proper, and after a call pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished thirty days in two newspapers in the State, signed, by a majority of said board, when they may organize for business, appoint time and place for opening subscription boots, fix the number of shares and amount of each, the amount of per cent to be paid in on each share; and when the whole stock has been subscribed and at least ten per cent on the whole amount of stock paid in, call a meeting of the stockholders for permanent organization by thirty days&#8217; publication in two newspapers in the State of Texas, and such other newspapers outside of the State as may be directed by the board; and in said permanent organization the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders may make and adopt all the by-laws, rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions deemed necessary for the general government of the company, which any future meeting of the stockholders may umber of permanent directors and their term of office; ay umber of permanent directors and their term of office; may provide for an executive committee of said board, and fix its powers, and such other things as they may deem necessary for the government of their company; and the seal of said company may be determined or altered by the directors, or the name of the company changed by them, and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have the right to receive subscriptions to aidnim the building of their said road, from individuals, corporation,, cities, towns, or counties, in lands, bonds, notes, or other property, conditional or unconditional, as the company through its agents or the parties may agree, payable to the president of said company or his successors, and the right to, enforce the payment of the same, or of any written agree<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to subscribe for stock, by suit in the courts of the couny^, in the name of the president or any assignee of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said company is hereby authorized and empowered to own, construct, maintain, equip, and op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate a continuous line of railroad and telegraph, together with all the rights and appurtenances thereto belonging, or in any way incident or appertaining. Said railroad Shalt be built the most direct and practicable route between the terminal points, to-wit: the city of Jefferson in the county of Marion, to a point on Red River, in Lamar county, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the mouth of Bois D&#8217;Arc and the mouth of Sanders Creek, where the south branch of the Missouri, Kansas and<pb n="346" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas railroad shall cross Red River, via Paris, Texas; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that in all cases where the located line of said road shall pass within four miles of any county seat, said company shall build to such town and maintain and operate a freight and passenger depot within one-half mile of the public square of such town. They may make such connections with any other road or roads as they may by agreement with them be able to do, and may make and construct any tap or branch of their road, not to exceed twenty-five miles in length; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided further, said company shall not consolidate with any other road in the State, except by and with the consent of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said company shall have the right of way over the lands of the State of Texas, on their line, and over any lands by whomsoever owned, subject to the general law of the State, governing such cases, for a width of two hundred feet, and the usual depots, turn-outs, machine shops, etc., and the usual rights of railroads to cross other roads, streams, etc., and shall commence the construction of their said road at any point on said line, which they may deem most advisable, within one year after said permanent organization of said company has been completed, and shall complete and put in running order twenty miles of said road within one year thereafter, and twenty-five miles each succeeding year, until said line is com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted; and on failure to do so, said company shall forfeit all benefits under this charter, except upon completed road.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The State of Texas hereby donates and grants to the said company out of any unlocated public domain of the State sixteen sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railroad constructed and put in substantial running order by them within the State; and whenever any section of ten miles of said road has been completed, the said company, through its presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent or secretary, may give notice of the same to the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of this State, in writing, whose duty it shall be, upon the receipt of such notice, to order the State engineer, if there be one, or if not, to appoint a skillful engineer to examine said section of said road, and report, under oath; and if said section of ten miles of said road be found to be constructed and in running order, in a substantial manner, then the Governor shall certify the same to the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, and he shall issue to said company sixteen land certificates, of six hundred and forty<pb n="347" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>acres each, for each and every mile of road so constructed and put in running order, and in like manner with each and every succeeding section of ten miles of said road, until the whole has been completed; all the certificates issued as above to said company shall be located by them in alternate sections, that is to say, for every sixteen sections located by said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany for its own use, said company shall locate also at the same time other sixteen sections of land for the State, and return the field notes and maps of the whole thirty-two sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who shall number said sections so surveyed, and issue patents to said company for the sections numbered in odd numbers, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serving the even numbers for the school fund; and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall alienate their said lands acquired under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, except so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the uses and successful operation of their said road as follows; one fourth in eight years, one fourth in twelve years, one fourth in sixteen years, and one fourth in twenty years, from the date of the location of the same; and on fail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure to comply with the provisions of this section, or for viola<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of same, said company shall forfeit all benefits under this charter; provided, that the State shall in no case be lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble for a deficiency of public domain, and no land certificate issued under the provisions of this act which may not be located because of the previous exhaustion of the public do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main, shall ever constitute any claim against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Said company shall be subject to all general laws now in force, or that may hereafter be enacted in this State regulating railroad companies, both as to rates of freight and passage, as well as to the conduct of its officers and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployees.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said company shall be liable to all the restrictions imposed on railroads by any general railroad law of this State, and shall be entitled to any of the benefits conferred by the same, and said road shall be of the uniform gauge of four feet eight and one-half inches.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The Legislature shall have full authority to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late the charges for freight and passengers on said railroad.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="348" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an Act to incorporate the Town of Ysleta, in El Paso County, approved May 9, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That &#8220;An Act to incorporate the town of Ysleta, in El Paso county,&#8221; approved May 9, 1871, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force sixty days after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the Title and Section one of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to Incorporate the Bryan Real Estate and Build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Association,&#8221; approved May 25, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the title of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate the Bryan Real Estate and Building Association,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved May 25, 1871, be so amended as to read hereafter as follows: &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Bryan Real Estate and Eire Insurance Association.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section one of said act be so amended as to read as follows: &#8220;Section 1. That H. M. Moore. W. G. Bunger, C. F. Moore, Spencer Ford, S. D. Conger, Frank Clark, M. W. McCraw, C. W. Gardiner, W. H. Flippin, and T. T. Smothers, and their associates and successors, he and they are hereby created and established a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8216;Bryan Real Estate and Fire Insur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance Association,&#8217; with capacity in said corporate name to make contracts; to hold, buy and sell property, both real and personal; to contract and execute leases; to take grants and gifts; to execute deeds and mortgages and deeds of trust; to have succession and a common seal; to issue policies of fire insurance to any person or firm, and to receive therefor such rates of insurance as the association may direct; to appoint by power of attorney or otherwise such agents as they may desire to attend to the business of the associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="349" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="83" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion, and in every act, perform, receive and discharge all the rights, privileges and immunities of a general fire insur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance company under the laws of the State; to make by-laws for the government and regulation of its affairs; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; to declare dividends and make divisions of property; to loan its moneys to any person or persons, on any securities it may think proper, and to do and perform all such things as may be necessary and proper for and incident to the fulfillment of its obligations and maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the laws of this State; provided, that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to authorize this corporation to use its moneys in any manner which it may not be lawful for any citizen of this State-to do.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Lake City Railway Company and to aid the Construction of the said Railway.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, Wm. M. Harrison, W. Q. Bateman, L. A. Ellis, P. M. Graham, Julius Hey, M. Dopplemayer, Thos. B. Goyne, J. H. Bennis, and James Arbuckle, their associates and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors, are hereby created and established a body corporate and politic, under the name and title of &#8220;The Lake City Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way Company,&#8221; and the said corporation is hereby invested with the right and power to contract and be contracted with; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; buy and sell real and personal property for the use of and connected with the construction and maintenance of the said railway, and to do and perforin all such acts, and the adoption of by-laws, as may be necessary and proper to effect the objects of this in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporation, not inconsistent with the laws and Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said corporation is hereby invested with the authority, right and power to locate, construct and<pb n="350" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="84" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>maintain a railway of such gauge as will conform to the gauge of the connected lines from without the State, from the city of Jefferson, in Marion county, to the east line of the State of Texas, so as to connect with any line of railway which may be constructed to connect said city with the Mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sissippi river.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said company may be in any amount that the stockholders thereof or a majority of the same may determine, not exceeding one million of dollars, to be divided in shares of one hundred dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the persons named in the first section of this act, or a majority of them and their associates, are hereby appointed commissioners to open books, and to receive sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions to the stock of said company; and whenever said company shall procure the subscription to said stock in the sum of fifty thousand dollars, and have five per cent, paid thereon, said stockholders may hold an election for a president, vice-president and five directors to manage and control the affairs of said company in accordance with this act, and such by-laws as the stockholders may adopt, which said officers shall hold their offices for the term of one [year] and until their successors are elected and qualified, unless removed as the said by-laws may direct.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Before any such election for the officers of said company, notice by publication shall be given for not less than two weeks in a newspaper published in said city, and each share of stock, upon which all dues and installments have been paid, shall be entitled to one vote, either by the person of the owner or by proxy made in writing, signed by such owner. The president and vice-president shall be ex officio directors, and said officers and a majority of the directors shall form a quorum for the transaction of business, and may appoint a secretary, treasurer, and such other officers and agents as may by them be deemed necessary, and require from them such bonds with sureties as they may require for the faithful discharge of their respective duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the right of way is hereby granted, to said company to the extent of two hundred feet in width, where the same may pass over any of the public domain, including all lands necessary for stations, work shops, switches, side tracks, turntables and water tanks, and<pb n="351" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="85" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>when the same shall pass through lands of private persons the right of way may he secured in accordance with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The office or domicile of said company shall be located at said city of Jefferson, and suits may be prosecuted by the president or vice-president of said company, or main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained against said company by service on either of said offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said company shall construct said railroad to the said east line of this State within at least eighteen months from the time they may be able to effect a suitable connection with a railway that will complete a connection to the Mississippi river, or forfeit all rights under this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said railway company shall be entitled to have and receive from the State of Texas sixteen sections of land containing six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of constructed road. And when the Governor shall be informed that a section of ten miles or more of said railway shall have been completed, he shall at once appoint some competent person to inspect the same. The person so appointed shall without delay make an examination of the railway and make report w[h]ether or not the same has been constructed in accordance with the terms of this charter; and if said report shall be in the affirmation, the Governor shall immediately notify the Commissioner of the General Land Office, whose duty it shall be to issue and deliver to said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany on demand sixteen certificates for land for six hundred and forty acres each for each and every mile of railroad so completed, which said certificates may be located and patented on any of the public domain of this State according to the general law on the principle of alternate sections; provided, the State shall not be in anywise liable for any deficiency in public domain.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the said railway company shall be authorized to establish such reasonable charges for passengers and freight, as it may deem proper, not to exceed the rate established by the general law of the State; and the said railway company shall be subject to such general laws as now exist or that may hereafter be enacted relating to railroads.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="352" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="86" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the San Antonio Street Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. H. Campman, H. B. Adams, Daniel Devine, E. D. L. Wicks, John Twohig, John Withers, and Peter Sheiner, of the city of San Antonio, county of Bexar, and their associates and successors, are hereby declared a body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio City Street Railway Company,&#8221; by which name they may contract and be contracted with; sue to final judgment and be sued; plead and be impleaded; issue bonds and borrow money for the construction, equipment and maintenance of their road; buy and sell real and personal estate, and gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally to do all acts necessary to carry out the objects and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The legal domicile of said company shall, be in the city of San Antonio.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The object of said company is declared to be to Trail d, equip, own and operate street railways in the streets of the city of San Antonio, and also, in such parts of Bexar county as may be continuations of said streets, or of said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roads; and this company, under this act, is authorized to build such roads on any street within the corporate limits of the city of San Antonio, as may hereafter be agreed upon by the mayor and aldermen of the city of San Antonio, and the said &#8220;San Antonio City Street Railway Company&#8221; with the right to use such motive power as may be agreed upon be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween this company and the city council of San Antonio.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock of this company shall be two hundred thousand dollars, divided into shares of twenty-five dollars each; said shares shall be transferable on the books of the company in person or by attorney.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Subscriptions for shares to the capital stock of this company shall be paid in such sums, and at such times, as may be agreed upon by the by-laws of said company. When any stockholder shall make default in the payment of the assessment of his stock, it, shall be sold by the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of said company, after thirty days&#8217; public notice, published in some newspaper in the city of San Antonio, which sale shall be an absolute conveyance in fee simple of<pb n="353" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="87" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>such stock to its purchaser, he also paying the remaining in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stallments which may be due.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This company shall, at their first meeting, make by-laws for its government, not inconsistent with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and laws of this State, or this act of incorporation. No by-laws shall take effect until approved by a majority of the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the parties named in the first section of this act, or a majority of them, are hereby declared commissioners, whose duty it shall be, within twenty-four months after the passage of this act, to organize said company as may be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termined by a majority of them. The stockholders shall elect a board of not less than five nor more than seven directors, who shall elect from their number a president; and they shall also elect such other officers as the by-laws may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all contracts made or entered into by and between the mayor and aldermen of the city of San Antonio and the said company, or any privileges or rights granted by the said mayor and aldermen of the city of San Antonio to the said company, shall be in all respects legal and binding on the aforesaid contracting parties.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. This charter shall remain in full force and effect for the period of fifty years.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all acts, laws, or parts of laws, ordinances or declarations conflicting with this act of incorporation be, and the same are hereby repealed; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that nothing herein contained shall annul or set aside any ordinances or laws of the city council of the city of San Antonio.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to organize and incorporate the Marshall, Texas, and Mansfield, Louisiana, Railroad Company,&#8221; approved April 27, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third (3d) section of an act to organize<pb n="354" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="88" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and incorporate the Marshall, Texas and Mansfield, Louisiana Railroad Company, approved April 27, 1871, shall read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, viz: Said company shall have the right to construct, and operate a first class single or double track railroad from Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shall, in Harrison county, to Elysian Fields, in said county, thence by the most practicable route to effect a connection with any railroad entering the State of Texas from the State of Louisiana, with the right to cross any other railroad track or tracks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The seventh (7th) section of said act shall read as follows, viz: Said company may begin the construction of said road at any point or points along their line that they may deem proper, and shall have completed and in running order the whole of said road within three years from and after the passage of this amendatory act; provided, that if said company shall fail to construct their road within the time above mentioned, they shall forfeit all rights and fran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chises conferred by this charter upon all of said route not then in actual operation; and provided further, that should such failure be caused by war, epidemic, floods or revolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the time of their prevalence shall be excepted from the limitation above mentioned, and shall not work a forfeiture in any respect.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Rusk Transportation Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That H. W. Graber, S. B. Barron, George D. Neely, J. J. Mallard, F. W. Bonner, M. J. Whitman, John T. Wiggins, Sam. A. Willson, B. B. Cannon, C. C. Francis, John G. Slover, W. Y. Long, J. C. Francis, R. H. Guinn, A. Jackson, James E. Dillard, James H. Sartain, T. L. Phillio, John R. Newton, R. B. Reagan, John B. Reagan, W. L. Byrd, and such others as they may associate with them, are hereby created a body politic and corporate, under the name of the &#8220;Rusk Transporta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion Company&#8221; and by such name they may sue and be sued, make contracts, have and hold real and personal property by grant, donation or purchase, or sell, alienate, or trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="355" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="89" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fer the same; said corporation shall have succession for ninety-nine years, and a corporate seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said persons named in the first section of this act shall constitute the first hoard of directors; they shall have the right to elect a president, vice-president, and secretary, treasurer, and attorney, the other officers and agents of the company shall be appointed in such manner as the directors may ordain and establish; the directors shall have power to make by-laws, rules and regulations for their government, so as to carry out the intent of this act, and to appoint an execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive committee and confer upon it such powers as they may see fit, not inconsistent with the laws of this State or the United States; to provide for the future election of officers, and to fix the place of the principal office of the company, and to change the same at pleasure; to provide for issuing of stock and the transfer of the same; to provide for the issuing of the bonds of the company, to mortgage and hypothecate the road bed, rolling stock, and all other property of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, to raise funds to build or equip a transportation road as hereinafter described.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said company shall have the right to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct, own, and operate a first-class tram-railway, or horse car road of whatever gauge they may see proper, from any point on the &#8220;International and Great Northern railroad,&#8221; in Cherokee county, by the most practicable route to the town of Rusk, in said Cherokee county; that said company shall have the right to connect their road with the Interna<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional and Great Northern railroad, and to connect with and cross any intervening road chartered in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said company shall have the right of way along their entire route, not to exceed two hundred feet in width, over all lands of the State, and the free use of rock, timber, gravel, and earth thereof, and the terms of the general laws of this State to procure the release of the right of way from the owners of lands along the route; and shall have the right to construct and operate a telegraph line along their en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tire route, and to build and construct bridges across all streams along their line; provided, that no right is given to obstruct navigation.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the capital stock of said company shall be five hundred thousand dollars, with the privilege of increas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing it to one million, divided into shares of fifty dollars each.</p>
<pb n="356" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="90" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. That said company shall have the whole line of said road completed in ten years from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That upon the completion by said company of a first-class tram-railway as provided for under the preceding section of this act, said company shall be entitled to have and receive a donation of eight sections of land, containing six hundred and forty (640) acres each, for each and every mile of said road, to be taken in alternate sections anywhere out of the public domain not otherwise appropriated; and it is hereby made the duty of the commissioner of the general land office to issue certificates for said land to the president of said company as soon as said road is completed and inspected, and when said certificates shall have been located, patents shall issue as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Said company shall have said lands surveyed and the field notes returned to the general land office at their own expense, and shall be required to alienate one-fourth of the same every five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the offspring of Julius Henry and Bertha Nathan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the child born unto the said Julius Henry and the said Bertha Nathan be, and the same is hereby declared to be legitimate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Austin and Pacific Short Line Railroad Company,&#8221; passed May 30, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the<pb n="357" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="91" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Austin and Pacific Short Line Railroad Company,&#8221; passed May 30, 1873, be and the same is hereby so amended as that section two of the same shall hereafter read as follows, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: &#8220;Sec. 2. The persons named in the first section of this act shall constitute the first board of directors, and shall hold their office for one year, or until their successors have been elected and qualified; a majority of them shall be a quorum, and their first meeting shall be held at such time and place as they may deem proper, and after a call published thirty days in two newspapers in the State of Texas, signed by a majority of said board, when they may organize for business, appoint time and place for opening subscription books, fix the number of shares, and the amount of each, the amount of per cent, to be paid in on each share, and when the whole stock has been subscribed and the per centum paid in, call a meeting of the stockholders for permanent organization, by thirty days publication in three newspapers in the State of Texas, and the said organization of said company shall be completed within six months after the passage of this act; and in said permanent organization the stockholders may make and adopt all the by-laws, rules and regulations deemed necessary for the general government of the company, which any future meeting of stockholders may alter or amend as be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />comes necessary; may determine the number of permanent directors, and their term of office; may provide for an ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecutive committee of said board, and fix its powers, and such other things as they deem necessary for the government of their company, and the seal of said company may be determ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ined or altered by the directors, or the name of the company changed by them; and said company shall have the right to receive subscriptions to aid in the building of their said road, or its branches, hereinafter provided for, from individuals, corporations, cities, towns, or counties, in lands, bonds, notes or other property, conditional or unconditional, as the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany through its agents or the parties may agree, payable to the president, of said company or his successors; and the right to enforce the payment of the same, or of any written agree<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to subscribe for stock, by suit in the courts of the county in the name of the president, or any assignee of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That section three of the above entitled act be and is hereby so amended as to read as follows, to-wit: &#8220;Sec. 3. Said company is hereby an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="358" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="92" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>thorized and empowered to own, construct, maintain, equip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and operate a continuous line of railroad and telegraph, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with all the rights and appurtenances thereto belong<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, or in any way incident or appertaining, commencing at the city of Austin, Texas, and running across the State of Texas to some point on the Texas Pacific Railroad be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the ninety-ninth and the one hundred and seventh de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grees of longitude, deemed most practicable by said company, after making its surveys. The said company is hereby further authorized and empowered, at any time they may deem it proper to do so, to extend their said line of railroad and tele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graph beyond the city of Austin to Indianola by the most practicable route, in order to form a seaboard terminus for their said railroad. They may make such connections with any other road or roads as they may by agreement with them be able to do, and when they deem that the necessities of the country and the demands of trade require the same, may make and construct any tap or branch of their road, not to exceed fifty miles in length; and the capital stock of said company shall be two hundred thousand dollars, with au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to raise the same to fifteen millions dollars, and said company may issue and sell its mortgage bonds to any amount it may deem proper, not to exceed ten million dollars, and said railroad shall pass through the town of Brownwood, in Brown county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to lease to the use of Travis county, certain land in the City of Austin, on which to erect a Courthouse and Jail, and to enable said county to build the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the north half of block No. (123) one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty-three, in the city of Austin, Travis county, Texas, be and the same is hereby leased for the term of ninety-nine years to said county of Travis, for public uses, on which to erect a courthouse and jail of not less value<pb n="359" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="93" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>than ninety thousand dollars; provided, said county of Travis shall not at any time, nor in any manner sell or otherwise dispose of said land; provided further, that said building shall be erected within five years from the passage of this act, or this grant shall become void; provided, Travis county shall be liable to suit, and all police laws and regulations, so far as paving side-walks and otherwise, so far as this property is concerned, in the same manner as citizens of the city of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin are; provided further, that should the State hereafter at any time desire so to do, it shall have the right to annul said lease by paying to the said county of Travis the full value of all improvements on said lot.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act, to incorporate the &#8220;Orange and Bolivar Point Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company,&#8221; and aid in the construction of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Jerome Swinford, Alexander Gilmer, R. H. Smith, F. C. McReynolds, N. J. Moore, J. N. Vaughn,, James S. Grinnen, Isaac G. Williams, and Levi Jones, of the State of Texas, and W. F. Hollister and Alvin Burt, of the State of Hew York, and all such persons as shall or may be asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciated with them and their successors, are hereby created a body politic and corporate, in fact and in law; by the name of the &#8220;Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company,&#8221; and by that name shall have perpetual succession, and shall be able to sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded; defend and be defended in all courts of law and equity, and make and have a common seal, and the same to alter at pleasure of the board of directors.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company and corporation is authorized to lay out, construct, finish and maintain, operate and enjoy a continuous railroad and telegraph line with all appurtenances, namely: Beginning at the town of Orange, county of Orange, thence in a south-westerly direction, by the way of Sabine Pass, county of Jefferson, to Bolivar Point, in Galveston county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the amount of stock to be subscribed, necessary to organization, shall not be<pb n="360" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="94" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>less than twenty-live thousand dollars, in shares of one hundred dollars each, of which amount of stock ten per cent, shall have been paid in. That the capital stock of said corporation shall not be less than one hundred thousand dollars, and shall not exceed three millions of dollars, unless by a majority of the stockholders, each share of stock being entitled to one vote, which capital stock shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the payment on said shares of stock shall be made in such manner and upon such notice as may be made and provided by the board of directors; provided, that payments on said shares of stock shall not exceed twenty-five per cent, thereof at any one time, nor be made oftener than once everv sixty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted. That the first meeting of the above incorporators shall be held at the domicile, in this State, of said company within a year from the passage of this act,; which domicile shall be definitely located by the above named incorporation at their first meeting; and on designating the domicile of said company as aforesaid, the said company shall immediately report the same to the General Land Office of this State, under the seal of the company. A notice of said meeting shall be published in a newspaper published along or on the proposed line of said road.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That at the first meeting of the said incorporators, they shall elect a president, vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />president, and secretary, and immediately open books for the subscription of the stock necessary for organization; upon taking which stock, ten per cent of which shall be paid in, they shall, elect a president, vice-president, and thirteen di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, each share of stock as aforesaid being entitled to one vote; on which complete organization they shall as soon as practicable, open books for subscription to the capital stock of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all suits for said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall be prosecuted in the name of the president of said corporation, and all notices and legal process shall be served oh said officer, or in case of his death, absence, or resignation, upon the vice-president of said company. Annual meetings of the stockholders in said corporation, for the choice of officers and the transaction of the business of the company, shall be held at the domicile of the company at such times and upon such notice as may be prescribed by the by-laws.</p>
<pb n="361" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="95" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the said Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company shall have the power to make such by-laws and regulations as may be deemed best for the proper management and government of said company, the the same not to be inconsistent with the objects of this char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter or the laws of the State; each stockholder in the enactment of said by-laws shall be entitled to one vote for each share of stock held by him, and may vote in person or by written proxy. It shall further require a vote of the majority of the said stockholders to establish such by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the right of way is hereby granted to the said Orange and Bolivar Point Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company and its successors, for the construction of a railroad and telegraph as proposed; and the right of way is granted to said company to the extent of one hundred feet in width on each side of said railroad, including all nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary grounds for work shops, switches, sidings, turn-tables, depots and water-tanks. That the said Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company is hereby authorized to enter upon, take and hold any lands or premises that may be necessary for the construction and working of said road, not exceeding one hundred feet on each side of said road; and the said company shall have the right to cut and remove trees, drift and other material that might, by falling or drifting, encumber its road<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bed, although being or standing more than one hundred and fifty feet from the line of said road, and in case the owner of said land or premises and the said company cannot agree as to the value of the said land or premises so taken, or to be taken for the use of said company, the value thereof shall be deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined by the appraisal of three disinterested commissioners, who may be appointed upon application of either party, by the district court of the county where the land lies, and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, in their assessment of damages, shall appraise such lands or premises at what would have been the value if the road had not been built; and uopn return into court of such appraisement and payment into the same of [of] the estimat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed value for the benefit of the owner, said premises shall be deemed taken by said company, which shall acquire full title to the same for the purpose aforesaid; and either party being aggrieved at such appraisement, may, within thirty days after the same has been returned into said court, file an appeal<pb n="362" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="96" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>therefrom, and demand a jury of twelve men to estimate the damages sustained. Said appraisal shall not interfere with the rights of said company to enter upon said lands or prem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ises, or prevent the said company from continuing the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of said road. The said party appealing shall give bond with sufficient, surety or sureties, to be approved by the judge of said court, for any costs or damages that may arise on said appeal; and in case any of the lands or premises taken, or to be taken as aforesaid, shall be held by any infant heirs or insane person residing without the State of Texas, and not represented by any administrator or guardian, the said judge of said court may appoint a guardian or attorney ad hor. to appear in proper person in their behalf, who shall give bond for the faithful execution of his trust, who may represent in court the person or persons disqualified as aforesaid when ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in reference to the appraisement of the premises or land taken, or to be taken for the use of said company, shall be had with the same effect as has already been described as to the final vestment of title as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the said Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company may issue their first mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage bonds to an amount not exceeding forty thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per mile, having not less than twenty years to run, which bonds shall be a first lien upon said road, and the property and equipments of the same, and shall bear not more than eight per cent, interest per annum, payable semi-annually, in gold, at such times and places as said company may determine. Such bonds and mortgages shall be filed and recorded in the office of recorder of mortgages and deeds, in the county in which the domicile of the company is located.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this company shall have the right and the power to charge and collect such rates of freight and passage as the company may deem just and proper; provided, however, such charges do not exceed the rates as are now, or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be established by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company shall be entitled to receive from the State of Texas a grant of sixteen sections of land for every mile of its road hereafter constructed under the provisions of this act, and put in good running order in this State; and said company shall alienate the lands hereby granted and donated, except so far as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the ordinary uses and operating said road, as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="363" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="97" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>lows, viz: one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in twelve years, one-fourth in sixteen years, and the remaining one-fourth in twenty years from the date of the location of the certificates, in such manner that the whole of such lands shall pass out, of the hands of said company within twenty years after the date of their location; provided, that said lands shall not be alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated to any other railroad company or corporation, except, so far as may be necessary for the proper use and conducting of the business of such company or corporation, nor shall said lands be alienated to any individual, firm or corporation in trust for said railroad company, or to any firm or company, of which any officer or stockholder of said railroad company is a member; and a failure to comply with the provisions of this act, and the general laws of the State on the subject, or a violation of the provisions of this act and such general laws, shall work a forfeiture of all benefits of this act; provided, that the State of Texas shall not be liable for any deficiency in lands; provided further, the gauge of said road shall not exceed four feet eight inches and a half, and not less than three feet in width.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That whenever said company shall have com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted and put in good running order, as provided in this act, ten miles or more of its road, they may give notice thereof to the Governor of the State, whose duty it shall be to appoint some skillful engineer (if there be no State Engineer) to exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine said completed road, and if, upon the report of said en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gineer under oath, it shall appear that said road has been con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed and equipped in a good and substantial manner, and in accordance with the provisions of the charter of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, this act, and the general laws in the State at the time regulating railroads, thereupon it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State to issue to said company certificates of six hundred and forty acres each to the amount of sixteen sections per mile so completed and reported, which said certificates shall be located and sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed in alternate sections, the field notes and maps returned to the General Land Office, and the odd sections patented to said company, and the even sections being reserved to the State for the school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That this charter shall remain in force for the period of ninety-nine years from the date of the passage of this act; provided, that if the gauge of [of] said road<pb n="364" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="98" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be less than, four feet eight and one-half inches, then it shall be entitled to receive certificates for twelve sections of land for each mile; and provided further, that the State shall not be held liable for any deficiency of the public domain upon which to locate said certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4,1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate the Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company, and aid in the Construction of the same,&#8221; passed at the First Session of the Fourteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the before named Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company shall finish and complete at least twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five miles of said road within three years, and twenty-five miles each succeeding year, until the whole of said road is completed, otherwise its rights granted in said act shall be forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, 1874</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="365" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="99" />
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, A. W. DeBerry, Secretary of State for the State of Texas, certify that, the acts contained in this volume are true copies taken from the originals in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared. And I further certify that the first session of the Fourteenth Legislature of said State commenced at the city of Austin on Tuesday, the thirteenth day of January, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and seventy-four, and adjourned on the fourth day of May, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and seventy-four.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and caused the seal of the Department of State to [Seal.] be affixed, at the city of Austin, this the twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fifth day of July, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and seventy-four.</p>
<closer>
<signed>A. W. DEBEREY, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="366" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="100" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO THE SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<p>Agricultural, Mechanical and Blood Stock Association&#8212;act to incorporate, amended................................... 32</p>
<p>Alamo Rifles of San Antonio&#8212;act to incorporate............ 62</p>
<p>Angelina County&#8212;powers of an aet to levy special tax in, suspended.................................... 35</p>
<p>Austin and Pacific Short Line Railroad Company&#8212;act to incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, amended.................... 90</p>
<p>Austin&#8212;certain lands in the city of, leased to Travis county on which to erect a courthouse and jail............... 93</p>
<p>Bowie County&#8212;Act to authorize the transcript of the record of, amended......................... 30</p>
<p>Brownsville&#8212;act to incorporate the city of, amended............. 3</p>
<p>Brenham&#8212;act supplemental to an act to incorporate the city of 26</p>
<p>Bryan Real Estate and Building Association&#8212;act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate, amended....................... 82</p>
<p>Caddo, Paris and Jefferson Branch, of Missouri, Kansas and Texas Railroad Company&#8212;act to incorporate........... 78</p>
<p>Cameron County&#8212;county court of, authorized to issue bonds.. 24</p>
<p>Carthage&#8212;election for a corporation for the town of, validated.. 59</p>
<p>Comanche County&#8212;act authorizing county court of, to issue bonds, amended..................... 51</p>
<p>El Paso County&#8212;atet to encourage irrigation in............ 44</p>
<p>Galveston Bank and Trust. Company&#8212;act to incorporate, amended..............33</p>
<p>Galveston&#8212;act to incorporate the city of, amended............... 22</p>
<p>Gathings, James J.&#8212;act to (provide for re-payment of money illegally extorted from.................. 33</p>
<p>Gonzales Tap Railway Company&#8212;act to incorporate.......... 51</p>
<p>Headlight&#8212;of Louis Rosseau, act relating to............ 35</p>
<p>Hearne, Belton and Northwestern R. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate 46</p>
<p>Henderson and Overton Branch R. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate.. 60</p>
<p>Henry, Julius, and Bertha Nathan&#8212;act to legalize the off<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spring of...................... 90</p>
<p>Houston and Brazos Canal and Nay. Co.&#8212;ant to. incorporate and grant aid to................ 65</p>
<p>supplement............................ 69</p>
<p>Houston City&#8212;-the several acts incorporating, consolidated and amended..................... 4</p>
<p>International and Great Northern R. R. Co.&#8212;authorized to issue bonds.................. 44</p>
<p>International R. R. Co.&#8212;act to limit the amount to be issued to, in bonds of the State..................... 49</p>
<p>act to grant lands to, in lieu of bonds on a certain por<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of its line................... 75</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Railroads&#8212;Orange, Jasper and Shelby Railroad Company, to aid in the construction of............. 36</p>
<p>South Western Railroad Company, to- slid in the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of.......................... 38</p>
<pb n="367" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="101" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Incorporations &#8212; International and Great Northern Railroad Company authorized to issue bonds................... 44</p>
<p>Hearne, Belton and North-Western Railroad Company, to aid in the construction of................... 46</p>
<p>International Railroad Company, act limiting amount in State bonds to be issued to................ 49</p>
<p>Gonzales Tap Railway Company................... 51</p>
<p>Texas Midland, Gulf and New Orleans Railway, to aid in the construction of..................... 54</p>
<p>Texas Midland, Gulf and New Orleans Railway, charter amended......................... 59</p>
<p>Henderson and Overton Branch Railway Company........... 60</p>
<p>South-western and Bio Grande Railroad Company, to aid in the construction of......................... 70</p>
<p>International Railroad. Company, to grant land in lieu of bonds on a portion of its line.................... 75</p>
<p>Rockport, Fulton, Laredo and Mexican Pacific Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, name changed................... 77</p>
<p>Caddo, Pans and Jefferson Branch of the Missouri, Kansas and Texas Railroad Company............... 78</p>
<p>Lake City Railway Company, to aid in the construction of.. 83</p>
<p>San Antonio Street Railway Company................ 86</p>
<p>Marshall, Texas, and Mansfiled Luisiana, Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, charter amended....................... 87</p>
<p>Austin and Pacific Short Line Railroad Company, charter amended...................... 90</p>
<p>Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad Company, to aid in the construction of....................... 93</p>
<p>Orange and Bolivar Point Railroad, supplement........... 98</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Banks&#8212;Galveston Bank and Trust Company, amended...................... 33</p>
<p>Texas Banking and Insurance Company, amended......... 34</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Cities and Towns&#8212;Brownsville, city of, amended 3</p>
<p>Houston, city of, amended............... 4</p>
<p>Galveston, city of, amended.......................22</p>
<p>Brenham, city of, supplement..............................26</p>
<p>Jefferson, city of, amended.......................28</p>
<p>Carthage, town of, election for corporation validated...... 59</p>
<p>Ysleta. town of, act to incorporate repealed.............. 82</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Canals&#8212;Houston and Brazos Canal and Navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation Company, to grant State aid to.......... 65</p>
<p>Houston and Brazos Canal and Navigation Company, sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement................ 69</p>
<p>Incorporations &#8212; Associations &#8212; Agricultural, Mechanical and Blood Stock................... 32</p>
<p>Bryan Real Estate and Building................. 82</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Miscellaneous- Alamo Rifles of San Antonio..62</p>
<p>Rusk Transportation Company............88</p>
<p>Waco Lodge, No. 70, Independent Order of Odd Fellows.... 24</p>
<p>Irrigation&#8212;act to encourage in El Paso county.............. 44</p>
<p>Jefferson&#8212;act to incorporate the city of, amended........... 28</p>
<p>Lake City Railway Company&#8212;act to incorporate.......... 83</p>
<p>Leon County&#8212;an act to authorize the police court of to levy a special tax to build a jail, re-enacted...................... 1</p>
<pb n="368" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="102" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Liquors&#8212;to prohibit sale of, within two miles of Moscow Ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonic High School, repealed............. 31</p>
<p>Melrose Masonic Institute, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.......................... 64</p>
<p>Millican, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.............. 64</p>
<p>Baylor University, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........ 64</p>
<p>New Hope Church and school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............64</p>
<p>Pleasant Grove Church, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........................ 64</p>
<p>Mt. Zabor Church, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.............. 64</p>
<p>Antioch Church, to prohibit sale of within two miles of......... 64</p>
<p>Maysfield Academy, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.. 64</p>
<p>Hepziah Church and school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of................... 64</p>
<p>Iradell School, to<smcap><sup> </sup></smcap>prohibit sale of within two miles of................ 64</p>
<p>White House Church and Academy, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........ 64</p>
<p>Peoria, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.................. 64</p>
<p>Lost Prairie, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.......... 64</p>
<p>Mt. Pleasant camp-ground, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.......................64</p>
<p>Ladonia Male and Female Seminary, to prohibit sale of within two miles of...................... 64</p>
<p>Douglassville College, to prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Weston school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Lancaster Masonic Institute to prohibit sale of within two miles of............... 64</p>
<p>Powell Dale, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............. 64</p>
<p>Merrilltown, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........... 64</p>
<p>Dresden school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Hooker&#8217;s school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Bristol, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............ 64</p>
<p>Forest Grove Chuitah, to prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Garden Valley, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.......... 64</p>
<p>Liberty Church, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.... 64</p>
<p>Woodbury, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.......... 64</p>
<p>Evans school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............ 64</p>
<p>Turner&#8217;s Point Academy, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............ 64</p>
<p>Fitzgerald school-house, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........................ 64</p>
<p>Howard and Tunshire, to -prohibit sale of within two miles of 64</p>
<p>Blossom Prairie Depot, to prohibit sale olf within two miles of..................... 64</p>
<p>Aurora, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.............. 64</p>
<p>Moulton, to prohibit sale of within two miles of........... 64</p>
<p>Heffner&#8217;s Chapel, to prohibit sale of within two miles of.... 64</p>
<p>Mantua, to prohibit sale of within two miles of............ 64</p>
<p>Liberty Fire Company No. 2 of Houston&#8212;authorized to raise and administer a charity fund...................... 76</p>
<p>Marshall, Texas, and Mansfield, Louisiana R. R. Co.&#8212;act to organize and incorporate, amended............... 87</p>
<p>Moscow&#8212;an act prohibiting the sale of liquors within two miles of, repealed......................... 31</p>
<p>Nathan, Bertha and Julius, Henry&#8212;an act to legalize the off<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spring of........................ 90</p>
<pb n="369" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="103" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Odd Fellows, Independent Order&#8212;Waco Lodge, No. 70, incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated..................... 24</p>
<p>Orange, Jasper and Shelby R. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate, amended 36</p>
<p>Orange and Bolivar Point B. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate........... 93</p>
<p>supplement................. 98</p>
<p>Powers, Josiah&#8212;unconditional certificate of land issued to, legal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized....................... 60</p>
<p>Railroads&#8212;(See Incorporations.)</p>
<p>Records&#8212;act authorizing transcript of, sof Bowie county, amended 30</p>
<p>Rosseau, Louis&#8212;act relating to headright claim of............ 35</p>
<p>Rockport, Fulton, Laredo and Mexican Pacific R. R. Co.&#8212;an act to amend caption and change name of.................... 77</p>
<p>Rusk Transportation Company&#8212;act to incorporate.................. 88</p>
<p>San Antonio Street Ry. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate.............. 86</p>
<p>Smith, E. M.&#8212;appropriation to pay judgment in favor of................ 31</p>
<p>South-Western R. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate.......... 38</p>
<p>South-Western and Rio Grande R. R. Co.&#8212;act to incorporate.... 70</p>
<p>Tax&#8212;county court of Tyler county authorized, to levy for cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain purposes.................. 29</p>
<p>Texas Banking and Insurance Co.-act to incorporate, amended 34</p>
<p>Texas Midland, Gulf and New Orleans Ry.&#8212;act to incorporate.. 54</p>
<p>act supplementary and amendatory....................59</p>
<p>Texas and Mexican -Pacific R. R. Co.&#8212;Rockport, Fulton, Laredo and Mexican Pacific Railroad Company, name changed to 77</p>
<p>Travis County&#8212;an act to lease to, certain land in the city of Austin, on which to build a courthouse and jail.............. 92</p>
<p>Tyler County&#8212;county court of, authorized to levy a special tax for certain purposes............... 29</p>
<p>Waco Lodge, No. 70, I. 0. 0. F.&#8212;act to incorporate.......... 24</p>
<p>Ysleta&#8212;act to incorporate the town of, repealed..................... 82</p>
<pb n="370" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="104" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
